callback([{"num":0,"sample":"T1A01","correct":"D","question":"[97.3(a)(4)] For whom is the Amateur Radio Service intended?","answers":{"a":"A. Persons who have messages to broadcast to the public","b":"B. Persons who need communications for the activities of their immediate family members, relatives and friends","c":"C. Persons who need two-way communications for personal reasons","d":"D. Persons who are interested in radio technique solely with a personal aim and without pecuniary interest"}},{"num":1,"sample":"T1A02","correct":"C","question":"[97.1] What agency regulates and enforces the rules for the Amateur Radio Service in the United States?","answers":{"a":"A. FEMA","b":"B. The ITU","c":"C. The FCC","d":"D. Homeland Security"}},{"num":2,"sample":"T1A03","correct":"D","question":"Which part of the FCC rules contains the rules and regulations governing the Amateur Radio Service?","answers":{"a":"A. Part 73","b":"B. Part 95","c":"C. Part 90","d":"D. Part 97"}},{"num":3,"sample":"T1A04","correct":"C","question":"[97.3(a)(23)] Which of the following meets the FCC definition of harmful interference?","answers":{"a":"A. Radio transmissions that annoy users of a repeater","b":"B. Unwanted radio transmissions that cause costly harm to radio station apparatus","c":"C. That which seriously degrades, obstructs, or repeatedly interrupts a radio communication service operating in accordance with the Radio Regulations","d":"D. Static from lightning storms"}},{"num":4,"sample":"T1A05","correct":"D","question":"[97.3(a)(40)] What is the FCC Part 97 definition of a space station?","answers":{"a":"A. Any multi-stage satellite","b":"B. An Earth satellite that carries one of more amateur operators","c":"C. An amateur station located less than 25 km above the Earth's surface","d":"D. An amateur station located more than 50 km above the Earth's surface"}},{"num":5,"sample":"T1A06","correct":"C","question":"[97.3(a)(43)] What is the FCC Part 97 definition of telecommand?","answers":{"a":"A. An instruction bulletin issued by the FCC","b":"B. A one-way radio transmission of measurements at a distance from the measuring instrument","c":"C. A one-way transmission to initiate, modify or terminate functions of a device at a distance","d":"D. An instruction from a VEC"}},{"num":6,"sample":"T1A07","correct":"C","question":"[97.3(a)(45)] What is the FCC Part 97 definition of telemetry?","answers":{"a":"A. An information bulletin issued by the FCC","b":"B. A one-way transmission to initiate, modify or terminate functions of a device at a distance","c":"C. A one-way transmission of measurements at a distance from the measuring instrument","d":"D. An information bulletin from a VEC"}},{"num":7,"sample":"T1A08","correct":"B","question":"[97.3(a)(22)] Which of the following entities recommends transmit/receive channels and other parameters for auxiliary and repeater stations?","answers":{"a":"A. Frequency Spectrum Manager","b":"B. Frequency Coordinator","c":"C. FCC Regional Field Office","d":"D. International Telecommunications Union"}},{"num":8,"sample":"T1A09","correct":"C","question":"[97.3(a)(22)] Who selects a Frequency Coordinator?","answers":{"a":"A. The FCC Office of Spectrum Management and Coordination Policy","b":"B. The local chapter of the Office of National Council of Independent Frequency Coordinators","c":"C. Amateur operators in a local or regional area whose stations are eligible to be auxiliary or repeater stations","d":"D. FCC Regional Field Office"}},{"num":9,"sample":"T1A10","correct":"A","question":"[97.3(a)(5)] What is the FCC Part 97 definition of an amateur station?","answers":{"a":"A. A station in an Amateur Radio Service consisting of the apparatus necessary for carrying on radio communications","b":"B. A building where Amateur Radio receivers, transmitters, and RF power amplifiers are installed","c":"C. Any radio station operated by a non-professional","d":"D. Any radio station for hobby use"}},{"num":10,"sample":"T1A11","correct":"C","question":"[97.3(a)(7)] Which of the following stations transmits signals over the air from a remote receive site to a repeater for retransmission?","answers":{"a":"A. Beacon station","b":"B. Relay station","c":"C. Auxiliary station","d":"D. Message forwarding station"}},{"num":11,"sample":"T1B01","correct":"B","question":"[97.3(a)(28)] What is the ITU?","answers":{"a":"A. An agency of the United States Department of Telecommunications Management","b":"B. A United Nations agency for information and communication technology issues","c":"C. An independent frequency coordination agency","d":"D. A department of the FCC"}},{"num":12,"sample":"T1B02","correct":"B","question":"North American amateur stations are located in which ITU region?","answers":{"a":"A. Region 1","b":"B. Region 2","c":"C. Region 3","d":"D. Region 4"}},{"num":13,"sample":"T1B03","correct":"B","question":"[97.301(a)] Which frequency is within the 6 meter band?","answers":{"a":"A. 49.00 MHz","b":"B. 52.525 MHz","c":"C. 28.50 MHz","d":"D. 222.15 MHz"}},{"num":14,"sample":"T1B04","correct":"A","question":"[97.301(a)] Which amateur band are you using when your station is transmitting on 146.52 MHz?","answers":{"a":"A. 2 meter band","b":"B. 20 meter band","c":"C. 14 meter band","d":"D. 6 meter band"}},{"num":15,"sample":"T1B05","correct":"C","question":"[97.301(a)] Which 70 cm frequency is authorized to a Technician Class license holder operating in ITU Region 2?","answers":{"a":"A. 53.350 MHz","b":"B. 146.520 MHz","c":"C. 443.350 MHz","d":"D. 222.520 MHz"}},{"num":16,"sample":"T1B06","correct":"B","question":"[97.301(a)] Which 23 cm frequency is authorized to a Technician Class operator license?","answers":{"a":"A. 2315 MHz","b":"B. 1296 MHz","c":"C. 3390 MHz","d":"D. 146.52 MHz"}},{"num":17,"sample":"T1B07","correct":"D","question":"[97.301(a)] What amateur band are you using if you are transmitting on 223.50 MHz?","answers":{"a":"A. 15 meter band","b":"B. 10 meter band","c":"C. 2 meter band","d":"D. 1.25 meter band"}},{"num":18,"sample":"T1B08","correct":"C","question":"[97.303] What do the FCC rules mean when an amateur frequency band is said to be available on a secondary basis?","answers":{"a":"A. Secondary users of a frequency have equal rights to operate","b":"B. Amateurs are only allowed to use the frequency at night","c":"C. Amateurs may not cause harmful interference to primary users","d":"D. Secondary users are not allowed on amateur bands"}},{"num":19,"sample":"T1B09","correct":"D","question":"[97.101(a)] Why should you not set your transmit frequency to be exactly at the edge of an amateur band or sub-band?","answers":{"a":"A. To allow for calibration error in the transmitter frequency display","b":"B. So that modulation sidebands do not extend beyond the band edge","c":"C. To allow for transmitter frequency drift","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":20,"sample":"T1B10","correct":"C","question":"[97.305(c)] Which of the bands available to Technician Class operators have mode-restricted sub-bands?","answers":{"a":"A. The 6 meter, 2 meter, and 70 cm bands","b":"B. The 2 meter and 13 cm bands","c":"C. The 6 meter, 2 meter, and 1.25 meter bands","d":"D. The 2 meter and 70 cm bands"}},{"num":21,"sample":"T1B11","correct":"A","question":"[97.305 (a)(c)] What emission modes are permitted in the mode-restricted sub-bands at 50.0 to 50.1 MHz and 144.0 to 144.1 MHz?","answers":{"a":"A. CW only","b":"B. CW and RTTY","c":"C. SSB only","d":"D. CW and SSB"}},{"num":22,"sample":"T1C01","correct":"C","question":"[97.3(a)(11)(iii)] Which type of call sign has a single letter in both the prefix and suffix?","answers":{"a":"A. Vanity","b":"B. Sequential","c":"C. Special event","d":"D. In-memoriam"}},{"num":23,"sample":"T1C02","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following is a valid US amateur radio station call sign?","answers":{"a":"A. KMA3505","b":"B. W3ABC","c":"C. KDKA","d":"D. 11Q1176"}},{"num":24,"sample":"T1C03","correct":"A","question":"[97.117] What types of international communications are permitted by an FCC-licensed amateur station?","answers":{"a":"A. Communications incidental to the purposes of the amateur service and remarks of a personal character","b":"B. Communications incidental to conducting business or remarks of a personal nature","c":"C. Only communications incidental to contest exchanges, all other communications are prohibited","d":"D. Any communications that would be permitted on an international broadcast station"}},{"num":25,"sample":"T1C04","correct":"A","question":"When are you allowed to operate your amateur station in a foreign country?","answers":{"a":"A. When the foreign country authorizes it","b":"B. When there is a mutual agreement allowing third party communications","c":"C. When authorization permits amateur communications in a foreign language","d":"D. When you are communicating with non-licensed individuals in another country"}},{"num":26,"sample":"T1C05","correct":"A","question":"[97.303(h)] What must you do if you are operating on the 23 cm band and learn that you are interfering with a radiolocation station outside the United States?","answers":{"a":"A. Stop operating or take steps to eliminate the harmful interference","b":"B. Nothing, because this band is allocated exclusively to the amateur service","c":"C. Establish contact with the radiolocation station and ask them to change frequency","d":"D. Change to CW mode, because this would not likely cause interference"}},{"num":27,"sample":"T1C06","correct":"D","question":"[97.5(a)(2)] From which of the following may an FCC-licensed amateur station transmit, in addition to places where the FCC regulates communications?","answers":{"a":"A. From within any country that belongs to the International Telecommunications Union","b":"B. From within any country that is a member of the United Nations","c":"C. From anywhere within in ITU Regions 2 and 3","d":"D. From any vessel or craft located in international waters and documented or registered in the United States"}},{"num":28,"sample":"T1C07","correct":"B","question":"[97.23] What may result when correspondence from the FCC is returned as undeliverable because the grantee failed to provide the correct mailing address?","answers":{"a":"A. Fine or imprisonment","b":"B. Revocation of the station license or suspension of the operator license","c":"C. Require the licensee to be re-examined","d":"D. A reduction of one rank in operator class"}},{"num":29,"sample":"T1C08","correct":"C","question":"[97.25] What is the normal term for an FCC-issued primary station/operator license grant?","answers":{"a":"A. Five years","b":"B. Life","c":"C. Ten years","d":"D. Twenty years"}},{"num":30,"sample":"T1C09","correct":"A","question":"[97.21(a)(b)] What is the grace period following the expiration of an amateur license within which the license may be renewed?","answers":{"a":"A. Two years","b":"B. Three years","c":"C. Five years","d":"D. Ten years"}},{"num":31,"sample":"T1C10","correct":"C","question":"[97.5a] How soon may you operate a transmitter on an amateur service frequency after you pass the examination required for your first amateur radio license?","answers":{"a":"A. Immediately","b":"B. 30 days after the test date","c":"C. As soon as your name and call sign appear in the FCC's ULS database","d":"D. You must wait until you receive your license in the mail from the FCC"}},{"num":32,"sample":"T1C11","correct":"A","question":"[97.21(b)] If your license has expired and is still within the allowable grace period, may you continue to operate a transmitter on amateur service frequencies?","answers":{"a":"A. No, transmitting is not allowed until the ULS database shows that the license has been renewed","b":"B. Yes, but only if you identify using the suffix \"GP\"","c":"C. Yes, but only during authorized nets","d":"D. Yes, for up to two years"}},{"num":33,"sample":"T1D01","correct":"A","question":"[97.111(a)(1)] With which countries are FCC-licensed amateur stations prohibited from exchanging communications?","answers":{"a":"A. Any country whose administration has notified the ITU that it objects to such communications","b":"B. Any country whose administration has notified the United Nations that it objects to such communications","c":"C. Any country engaged in hostilities with another country","d":"D. Any country in violation of the War Powers Act of 1934"}},{"num":34,"sample":"T1D02","correct":"A","question":"[97.111(a)(5)] On which of the following occasions may an FCC-licensed amateur station exchange messages with a U.S. military station?","answers":{"a":"A. During an Armed Forces Day Communications Test","b":"B. During a Memorial Day Celebration","c":"C. During an Independence Day celebration","d":"D. During a propagation test"}},{"num":35,"sample":"T1D03","correct":"C","question":"[97.113(a)(4), 97.211(b), 97.217] When is the transmission of codes or ciphers allowed to hide the meaning of a message transmitted by an amateur station?","answers":{"a":"A. Only during contests","b":"B. Only when operating mobile","c":"C. Only when transmitting control commands to space stations or radio control craft","d":"D. Only when frequencies above 1280 MHz are used"}},{"num":36,"sample":"T1D04","correct":"A","question":"[97.113(a)(4), 97.113(e)] What is the only time an amateur station is authorized to transmit music?","answers":{"a":"A. When incidental to an authorized retransmission of manned spacecraft communications","b":"B. When the music produces no spurious emissions","c":"C. When the purpose is to interfere with an illegal transmission","d":"D. When the music is transmitted above 1280 MHz"}},{"num":37,"sample":"T1D05","correct":"A","question":"[97.113(a)(3)] When may amateur radio operators use their stations to notify other amateurs of the availability of equipment for sale or trade?","answers":{"a":"A. When the equipment is normally used in an amateur station and such activity is not conducted on a regular basis","b":"B. When the asking price is $100.00 or less","c":"C. When the asking price is less than its appraised value","d":"D. When the equipment is not the personal property of either the station licensee or the control operator or their close relatives"}},{"num":38,"sample":"T1D06","correct":"A","question":"[97.113(a)(4)] Which of the following types of transmissions are prohibited?","answers":{"a":"A. Transmissions that contain obscene or indecent words or language","b":"B. Transmissions to establish one-way communications","c":"C. Transmissions to establish model aircraft control","d":"D. Transmissions for third party communications"}},{"num":39,"sample":"T1D07","correct":"B","question":"[97.113(f)] When is an amateur station authorized to automatically retransmit the radio signals of other amateur stations?","answers":{"a":"A. When the signals are from an auxiliary, beacon, or Earth station","b":"B. When the signals are from an auxiliary, repeater, or space station","c":"C. When the signals are from a beacon, repeater, or space station","d":"D. When the signals are from an Earth, repeater, or space station"}},{"num":40,"sample":"T1D08","correct":"B","question":"[97.113] When may the control operator of an amateur station receive compensation for operating the station?","answers":{"a":"A. When engaging in communications on behalf of their employer","b":"B. When the communication is incidental to classroom instruction at an educational institution","c":"C. When re-broadcasting weather alerts during a RACES net","d":"D. When notifying other amateur operators of the availability for sale or trade of apparatus"}},{"num":41,"sample":"T1D09","correct":"A","question":"[97.113(b)] Under which of the following circumstances are amateur stations authorized to transmit signals related to broadcasting, program production, or news gathering, assuming no other means is available?","answers":{"a":"A. Only where such communications directly relate to the immediate safety of human life or protection of property","b":"B. Only when broadcasting communications to or from the space shuttle.","c":"C. Only where noncommercial programming is gathered and supplied exclusively to the National Public Radio network","d":"D. Only when using amateur repeaters linked to the Internet"}},{"num":42,"sample":"T1D10","correct":"D","question":"[97.3(a)(10)] What is the meaning of the term broadcasting in the FCC rules for the amateur services?","answers":{"a":"A. Two-way transmissions by amateur stations","b":"B. Transmission of music","c":"C. Transmission of messages directed only to amateur operators","d":"D. Transmissions intended for reception by the general public"}},{"num":43,"sample":"T1D11","correct":"A","question":"[97.113(a)(5)] Which of the following types of communications are permitted in the Amateur Radio Service?","answers":{"a":"A. Brief transmissions to make station adjustments","b":"B. Retransmission of entertainment programming from a commercial radio or TV station","c":"C. Retransmission of entertainment material from a public radio or TV station","d":"D. Communications on a regular basis that could reasonably be furnished alternatively through other radio services"}},{"num":44,"sample":"T1E01","correct":"A","question":"[97.7(a)] When must an amateur station have a control operator?","answers":{"a":"A. Only when the station is transmitting","b":"B. Only when the station is being locally controlled","c":"C. Only when the station is being remotely controlled","d":"D. Only when the station is being automatically controlled"}},{"num":45,"sample":"T1E02","correct":"D","question":"[97.7(a)] Who is eligible to be the control operator of an amateur station?","answers":{"a":"A. Only a person holding an amateur service license from any country that belongs to the United Nations","b":"B. Only a citizen of the United States","c":"C. Only a person over the age of 18","d":"D. Only a person for whom an amateur operator/primary station license grant appears in the FCC database or who is authorized for alien reciprocal operation"}},{"num":46,"sample":"T1E03","correct":"A","question":"[97.103(b)] Who must designate the station control operator?","answers":{"a":"A. The station licensee","b":"B. The FCC","c":"C. The frequency coordinator","d":"D. The ITU"}},{"num":47,"sample":"T1E04","correct":"D","question":"[97.103(b)] What determines the transmitting privileges of an amateur station?","answers":{"a":"A. The frequency authorized by the frequency coordinator","b":"B. The class of operator license held by the station licensee","c":"C. The highest class of operator license held by anyone on the premises","d":"D. The class of operator license held by the control operator"}},{"num":48,"sample":"T1E05","correct":"C","question":"[97.3(a)(14)] What is an amateur station control point?","answers":{"a":"A. The location of the station's transmitting antenna","b":"B. The location of the station transmitting apparatus","c":"C. The location at which the control operator function is performed","d":"D. The mailing address of the station licensee"}},{"num":49,"sample":"T1E06","correct":"B","question":"[97.109(d)] Under which of the following types of control is it permissible for the control operator to be at a location other than the control point?","answers":{"a":"A. Local control","b":"B. Automatic control","c":"C. Remote control","d":"D. Indirect control"}},{"num":50,"sample":"T1E07","correct":"D","question":"[97.103(a)] When the control operator is not the station licensee, who is responsible for the proper operation of the station?","answers":{"a":"A. All licensed amateurs who are present at the operation","b":"B. Only the station licensee","c":"C. Only the control operator","d":"D. The control operator and the station licensee are equally responsible"}},{"num":51,"sample":"T1E08","correct":"C","question":"[97.3(a)] What type of control is being used for a repeater when the control operator is not present at a control point?","answers":{"a":"A. Local control","b":"B. Remote control","c":"C. Automatic control","d":"D. Unattended"}},{"num":52,"sample":"T1E09","correct":"D","question":"[97.109(a)] What type of control is being used when transmitting using a handheld radio?","answers":{"a":"A. Radio control","b":"B. Unattended control","c":"C. Automatic control","d":"D. Local control"}},{"num":53,"sample":"T1E10","correct":"B","question":"[97.3] What type of control is used when the control operator is not at the station location but can indirectly manipulate the operating adjustments of a station?","answers":{"a":"A. Local","b":"B. Remote","c":"C. Automatic","d":"D. Unattended"}},{"num":54,"sample":"T1E11","correct":"D","question":"[97.103(a)] Who does the FCC presume to be the control operator of an amateur station, unless documentation to the contrary is in the station records?","answers":{"a":"A. The station custodian","b":"B. The third party participant","c":"C. The person operating the station equipment","d":"D. The station licensee"}},{"num":55,"sample":"T1F01","correct":"A","question":"What type of identification is being used when identifying a station on the air as \"Race Headquarters\"?","answers":{"a":"A. Tactical call","b":"B. Self-assigned designator","c":"C. SSID","d":"D. Broadcast station"}},{"num":56,"sample":"T1F02","correct":"C","question":"[97.119 (a)] When using tactical identifiers, how often must your station transmit the station's FCC-assigned call sign?","answers":{"a":"A. Never, the tactical call is sufficient","b":"B. Once during every hour","c":"C. Every ten minutes","d":"D. At the end of every communication"}},{"num":57,"sample":"T1F03","correct":"D","question":"[97.119(a)] When is an amateur station required to transmit its assigned call sign?","answers":{"a":"A. At the beginning of each contact, and every 10 minutes thereafter","b":"B. At least once during each transmission","c":"C. At least every 15 minutes during and at the end of a contact","d":"D. At least every 10 minutes during and at the end of a contact"}},{"num":58,"sample":"T1F04","correct":"C","question":"[97.119(b)] Which of the following is an acceptable language for use for station identification when operating in a phone sub-band?","answers":{"a":"A. Any language recognized by the United Nations","b":"B. Any language recognized by the ITU","c":"C. The English language","d":"D. English, French, or Spanish"}},{"num":59,"sample":"T1F05","correct":"B","question":"[97.119(b)] What method of call sign identification is required for a station transmitting phone signals?","answers":{"a":"A. Send the call sign followed by the indicator RPT","b":"B. Send the call sign using CW or phone emission","c":"C. Send the call sign followed by the indicator R","d":"D. Send the call sign using only phone emission"}},{"num":60,"sample":"T1F06","correct":"D","question":"[97.119(c)] Which of the following formats of a self-assigned indicator is acceptable when identifying using a phone transmission?","answers":{"a":"A. KL7CC stroke W3","b":"B. KL7CC slant W3","c":"C. KL7CC slash W3","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":61,"sample":"T1F07","correct":"D","question":"[97.119(c)] Which of the following restrictions apply when appending a self-assigned call sign indicator?","answers":{"a":"A. It must be more than three letters and less than five letters","b":"B. It must be less than five letters","c":"C. It must start with the letters AA through AL, K, N, or W and be not less than two characters or more than five characters in length","d":"D. It must not conflict with any other indicator specified by the FCC rules or with any call sign prefix assigned to another country"}},{"num":62,"sample":"T1F08","correct":"A","question":"[97.119(e)] When may a Technician Class licensee be the control operator of a station operating in an exclusive Extra Class operator segment of the amateur bands?","answers":{"a":"A. Never","b":"B. On Armed Forces Day","c":"C. As part of a multi-operator contest team","d":"D. When using a club station whose trustee is an Extra Class operator licensee"}},{"num":63,"sample":"T1F09","correct":"C","question":"[97.3(a)(39)] What type of amateur station simultaneously retransmits the signal of another amateur station on a different channel or channels?","answers":{"a":"A. Beacon station","b":"B. Earth station","c":"C. Repeater station","d":"D. Message forwarding station"}},{"num":64,"sample":"T1F10","correct":"A","question":"[97.205(g)] Who is accountable should a repeater inadvertently retransmit communications that violate the FCC rules?","answers":{"a":"A. The control operator of the originating station","b":"B. The control operator of the repeater","c":"C. The owner of the repeater","d":"D. Both the originating station and the repeater owner"}},{"num":65,"sample":"T1F11","correct":"A","question":"[97.115(a)] To which foreign stations do the FCC rules authorize the transmission of non-emergency third party communications?","answers":{"a":"A. Any station whose government permits such communications","b":"B. Those in ITU Region 2 only","c":"C. Those in ITU Regions 2 and 3 only","d":"D. Those in ITU Region 3 only"}},{"num":66,"sample":"T1F12","correct":"B","question":"[97.5(b)(2)] How many persons are required to be members of a club for a club station license to be issued by the FCC?","answers":{"a":"A. At least 5","b":"B. At least 4","c":"C. A trustee and 2 officers","d":"D. At least 2"}},{"num":67,"sample":"T1F13","correct":"B","question":"[97.103(c)] When must the station licensee make the station and its records available for FCC inspection?","answers":{"a":"A. Any time upon request by an official observer","b":"B. Any time upon request by an FCC representative","c":"C. 30 days prior to renewal of the station license","d":"D. 10 days before the first transmission"}},{"num":68,"sample":"T2A01","correct":"B","question":"What is the most common repeater frequency offset in the 2 meter band?","answers":{"a":"A. plus 500 kHz","b":"B. plus or minus 600 kHz","c":"C. minus 500 kHz","d":"D. Only plus 600 kHz"}},{"num":69,"sample":"T2A02","correct":"D","question":"What is the national calling frequency for FM simplex operations in the 70 cm band?","answers":{"a":"A. 146.520 MHz","b":"B. 145.000 MHz","c":"C. 432.100 MHz","d":"D. 446.000 MHz"}},{"num":70,"sample":"T2A03","correct":"A","question":"What is a common repeater frequency offset in the 70 cm band?","answers":{"a":"A. Plus or minus 5 MHz","b":"B. Plus or minus 600 kHz","c":"C. Minus 600 kHz","d":"D. Plus 600 kHz"}},{"num":71,"sample":"T2A04","correct":"B","question":"What is an appropriate way to call another station on a repeater if you know the other station's call sign?","answers":{"a":"A. Say \"break, break\" then say the station's call sign","b":"B. Say the station's call sign then identify with your call sign","c":"C. Say \"CQ\" three times then the other station's call sign","d":"D. Wait for the station to call \"CQ\" then answer it"}},{"num":72,"sample":"T2A05","correct":"C","question":"What should you transmit when responding to a call of CQ?","answers":{"a":"A. CQ followed by the other station's call sign","b":"B. Your call sign followed by the other station's call sign","c":"C. The other station's call sign followed by your call sign","d":"D. A signal report followed by your call sign"}},{"num":73,"sample":"T2A06","correct":"A","question":"What must an amateur operator do when making on-air transmissions to test equipment or antennas?","answers":{"a":"A. Properly identify the transmitting station","b":"B. Make test transmissions only after 10:00 p.m. local time","c":"C. Notify the FCC of the test transmission","d":"D. State the purpose of the test during the test procedure"}},{"num":74,"sample":"T2A07","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following is true when making a test transmission?","answers":{"a":"A. Station identification is not required if the transmission is less than 15 seconds","b":"B. Station identification is not required if the transmission is less than 1 watt","c":"C. Station identification is required only if your station can be heard","d":"D. Station identification is required at least every ten minutes during the test and at the end"}},{"num":75,"sample":"T2A08","correct":"D","question":"What is the meaning of the procedural signal \"CQ\"?","answers":{"a":"A. Call on the quarter hour","b":"B. A new antenna is being tested (no station should answer)","c":"C. Only the called station should transmit","d":"D. Calling any station"}},{"num":76,"sample":"T2A09","correct":"B","question":"What brief statement is often used in place of \"CQ\" to indicate that you are listening on a repeater?","answers":{"a":"A. Say \"Hello test\" followed by your call sign","b":"B. Say your call sign","c":"C. Say the repeater call sign followed by your call sign","d":"D. Say the letters \"QSY\" followed by your call sign"}},{"num":77,"sample":"T2A10","correct":"A","question":"What is a band plan, beyond the privileges established by the FCC?","answers":{"a":"A. A voluntary guideline for using different modes or activities within an amateur band","b":"B. A mandated list of operating schedules","c":"C. A list of scheduled net frequencies","d":"D. A plan devised by a club to use a frequency band during a contest"}},{"num":78,"sample":"T2A11","correct":"D","question":"[97.313(a)] What are the FCC rules regarding power levels used in the amateur bands?","answers":{"a":"A. Always use the maximum power allowed to ensure that you complete the contact","b":"B. An amateur may use no more than 200 watts PEP to make an amateur contact","c":"C. An amateur may use up to 1500 watts PEP on any amateur frequency","d":"D. An amateur must use the minimum transmitter power necessary to carry out the desired communication"}},{"num":79,"sample":"T2B01","correct":"C","question":"What is the term used to describe an amateur station that is transmitting and receiving on the same frequency?","answers":{"a":"A. Full duplex communication","b":"B. Diplex communication","c":"C. Simplex communication","d":"D. Half duplex communication"}},{"num":80,"sample":"T2B02","correct":"D","question":"What is the term used to describe the use of a sub-audible tone transmitted with normal voice audio to open the squelch of a receiver?","answers":{"a":"A. Carrier squelch","b":"B. Tone burst","c":"C. DTMF","d":"D. CTCSS"}},{"num":81,"sample":"T2B03","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following describes the muting of receiver audio controlled solely by the presence or absence of an RF signal?","answers":{"a":"A. Tone squelch","b":"B. Carrier squelch","c":"C. CTCSS","d":"D. Modulated carrier"}},{"num":82,"sample":"T2B04","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following common problems might cause you to be able to hear but not access a repeater even when transmitting with the proper offset?","answers":{"a":"A. The repeater receiver requires audio tone burst for access","b":"B. The repeater receiver requires a CTCSS tone for access","c":"C. The repeater receiver may require a DCS tone sequence for access","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":83,"sample":"T2B05","correct":"C","question":"What determines the amount of deviation of an FM signal?","answers":{"a":"A. Both the frequency and amplitude of the modulating signal","b":"B. The frequency of the modulating signal","c":"C. The amplitude of the modulating signal","d":"D. The relative phase of the modulating signal and the carrier"}},{"num":84,"sample":"T2B06","correct":"A","question":"What happens when the deviation of an FM transmitter is increased?","answers":{"a":"A. Its signal occupies more bandwidth","b":"B. Its output power increases","c":"C. Its output power and bandwidth increases","d":"D. Asymmetric modulation occurs"}},{"num":85,"sample":"T2B07","correct":"D","question":"What should you do if you receive a report that your station's transmissions are causing splatter or interference on nearby frequencies?","answers":{"a":"A. Increase transmit power","b":"B. Change mode of transmission","c":"C. Report the interference to the equipment manufacturer","d":"D. Check your transmitter for off-frequency operation or spurious emissions"}},{"num":86,"sample":"T2B08","correct":"B","question":"What is the proper course of action if your station's transmission unintentionally interferes with another station?","answers":{"a":"A. Rotate your antenna slightly","b":"B. Properly identify your transmission and move to a different frequency","c":"C. Increase power","d":"D. Change antenna polarization"}},{"num":87,"sample":"T2B09","correct":"A","question":"[97.119(b)(2)] Which of the following methods is encouraged by the FCC when identifying your station when using phone?","answers":{"a":"A. Use of a phonetic alphabet","b":"B. Send your call sign in CW as well as voice","c":"C. Repeat your call sign three times","d":"D. Increase your signal to full power when identifying"}},{"num":88,"sample":"T2B10","correct":"A","question":"What is the \"Q\" signal used to indicate that you are receiving interference from other stations?","answers":{"a":"A. QRM","b":"B. QRN","c":"C. QTH","d":"D. QSB"}},{"num":89,"sample":"T2B11","correct":"B","question":"What is the \"Q\" signal used to indicate that you are changing frequency?","answers":{"a":"A. QRU","b":"B. QSY","c":"C. QSL","d":"D. QRZ"}},{"num":90,"sample":"T2C01","correct":"C","question":"[97.103(a)] What set of rules applies to proper operation of your station when using amateur radio at the request of public service officials?","answers":{"a":"A. RACES Rules","b":"B. ARES Rules","c":"C. FCC Rules","d":"D. FEMA Rules"}},{"num":91,"sample":"T2C02","correct":"D","question":"[97.113 and FCC Public Notice DA 09-2259] Who must submit the request for a temporary waiver of Part 97.113 to allow amateur radio operators to provide communications on behalf of their employers during a government sponsored disaster drill?","answers":{"a":"A. Each amateur participating in the drill","b":"B. Any employer participating in the drill","c":"C. The local American Red Cross Chapter","d":"D. The government agency sponsoring the event"}},{"num":92,"sample":"T2C03","correct":"C","question":"[97.113] When is it legal for an amateur licensee to provide communications on behalf of their employer during a government sponsored disaster drill or exercise?","answers":{"a":"A. Whenever the employer is a not-for-profit organization","b":"B. Whenever there is a temporary need for the employer's business continuity plan","c":"C. Only when the FCC has granted a government-requested waiver","d":"D. Only when the amateur is not receiving compensation from his employer for the activity"}},{"num":93,"sample":"T2C04","correct":"D","question":"What do RACES and ARES have in common?","answers":{"a":"A. They represent the two largest ham clubs in the United States","b":"B. Both organizations broadcast road and weather traffic information","c":"C. Neither may handle emergency traffic supporting public service agencies","d":"D. Both organizations may provide communications during emergencies"}},{"num":94,"sample":"T2C05","correct":"B","question":"[97.3(a)(37), 97.407 ] What is the Radio Amateur Civil Emergency Service?","answers":{"a":"A. An emergency radio service organized by amateur operators","b":"B. A radio service using amateur stations for emergency management or civil defense communications","c":"C. A radio service organized to provide communications at civic events","d":"D. A radio service organized by amateur operators to assist non-military persons"}},{"num":95,"sample":"T2C06","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following is common practice during net operations to get the immediate attention of the net control station when reporting an emergency?","answers":{"a":"A. Repeat the words SOS three times followed by the call sign of the reporting station","b":"B. Press the push-to-talk button three times","c":"C. Begin your transmission with \"Priority\" or \"Emergency\" followed by your call sign","d":"D. Play a pre-recorded emergency alert tone followed by your call sign"}},{"num":96,"sample":"T2C07","correct":"C","question":"What should you do to minimize disruptions to an emergency traffic net once you have checked in?","answers":{"a":"A. Whenever the net frequency is quiet, announce your call sign and location","b":"B. Move 5 kHz away from the net's frequency and use high power to ask other hams to keep clear of the net frequency","c":"C. Do not transmit on the net frequency until asked to do so by the net control station","d":"D. Wait until the net frequency is quiet, then ask for any emergency traffic for your area"}},{"num":97,"sample":"T2C08","correct":"A","question":"What is usually considered to be the most important job of an amateur operator when handling emergency traffic messages?","answers":{"a":"A. Passing messages exactly as written, spoken or as received","b":"B. Estimating the number of people affected by the disaster","c":"C. Communicating messages to the news media for broadcast outside the disaster area","d":"D. Broadcasting emergency information to the general public"}},{"num":98,"sample":"T2C09","correct":"B","question":"[97.403] When may an amateur station use any means of radio communications at its disposal for essential communications in connection with immediate safety of human life and protection of property?","answers":{"a":"A. Only when FEMA authorizes it by declaring an emergency","b":"B. When normal communications systems are not available","c":"C. Only when RACES authorizes it by declaring an emergency","d":"D. Only when authorized by the local MARS program director"}},{"num":99,"sample":"T2C10","correct":"D","question":"What is the preamble in a formal traffic message?","answers":{"a":"A. The first paragraph of the message text","b":"B. The message number","c":"C. The priority handling indicator for the message","d":"D. The information needed to track the message as it passes through the amateur radio traffic handling system"}},{"num":100,"sample":"T2C11","correct":"A","question":"What is meant by the term \"check\" in reference to a formal traffic message?","answers":{"a":"A. The check is a count of the number of words or word equivalents in the text portion of the message","b":"B. The check is the value of a money order attached to the message","c":"C. The check is a list of stations that have relayed the message","d":"D. The check is a box on the message form that tells you the message was received"}},{"num":101,"sample":"T3A01","correct":"D","question":"What should you do if another operator reports that your station's 2 meter signals were strong just a moment ago, but now they are weak or distorted?","answers":{"a":"A. Change the batteries in your radio to a different type","b":"B. Turn on the CTCSS tone","c":"C. Ask the other operator to adjust his squelch control","d":"D. Try moving a few feet, as random reflections may be causing multi-path distortion"}},{"num":102,"sample":"T3A02","correct":"B","question":"Why are UHF signals often more effective from inside buildings than VHF signals?","answers":{"a":"A. VHF signals lose power faster over distance","b":"B. The shorter wavelength allows them to more easily penetrate the structure of buildings","c":"C. This is incorrect; VHF works better than UHF inside buildings","d":"D. UHF antennas are more efficient than VHF antennas"}},{"num":103,"sample":"T3A03","correct":"C","question":"What antenna polarization is normally used for long-distance weak-signal CW and SSB contacts using the VHF and UHF bands?","answers":{"a":"A. Right-hand circular","b":"B. Left-hand circular","c":"C. Horizontal","d":"D. Vertical"}},{"num":104,"sample":"T3A04","correct":"B","question":"What can happen if the antennas at opposite ends of a VHF or UHF line of sight radio link are not using the same polarization?","answers":{"a":"A. The modulation sidebands might become inverted","b":"B. Signals could be significantly weaker","c":"C. Signals have an echo effect on voices","d":"D. Nothing significant will happen"}},{"num":105,"sample":"T3A05","correct":"B","question":"When using a directional antenna, how might your station be able to access a distant repeater if buildings or obstructions are blocking the direct line of sight path?","answers":{"a":"A. Change from vertical to horizontal polarization","b":"B. Try to find a path that reflects signals to the repeater","c":"C. Try the long path","d":"D. Increase the antenna SWR"}},{"num":106,"sample":"T3A06","correct":"B","question":"What term is commonly used to describe the rapid fluttering sound sometimes heard from mobile stations that are moving while transmitting?","answers":{"a":"A. Flip-flopping","b":"B. Picket fencing","c":"C. Frequency shifting","d":"D. Pulsing"}},{"num":107,"sample":"T3A07","correct":"A","question":"What type of wave carries radio signals between transmitting and receiving stations?","answers":{"a":"A. Electromagnetic","b":"B. Electrostatic","c":"C. Surface acoustic","d":"D. Magnetostrictive"}},{"num":108,"sample":"T3A08","correct":"C","question":"What is the cause of irregular fading of signals from distant stations during times of generally good reception?","answers":{"a":"A. Absorption of signals by the \"D\" layer of the ionosphere","b":"B. Absorption of signals by the \"E\" layer of the ionosphere","c":"C. Random combining of signals arriving via different path lengths","d":"D. Intermodulation distortion in the local receiver"}},{"num":109,"sample":"T3A09","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following is a common effect of \"skip\" reflections between the Earth and the ionosphere?","answers":{"a":"A. The sidebands become reversed at each reflection","b":"B. The polarization of the original signal is randomized","c":"C. The apparent frequency of the received signal is shifted by a random amount","d":"D. Signals at frequencies above 30 MHz become stronger with each reflection"}},{"num":110,"sample":"T3A10","correct":"D","question":"What may occur if VHF or UHF data signals propagate over multiple paths?","answers":{"a":"A. Transmission rates can be increased by a factor equal to the number of separate paths observed","b":"B. Transmission rates must be decreased by a factor equal to the number of separate paths observed","c":"C. No significant changes will occur if the signals are transmitting using FM","d":"D. Error rates are likely to increase"}},{"num":111,"sample":"T3A11","correct":"C","question":"Which part of the atmosphere enables the propagation of radio signals around the world?","answers":{"a":"A. The stratosphere","b":"B. The troposphere","c":"C. The ionosphere","d":"D. The magnetosphere"}},{"num":112,"sample":"T3B01","correct":"C","question":"What is the name for the distance a radio wave travels during one complete cycle?","answers":{"a":"A. Wave speed","b":"B. Waveform","c":"C. Wavelength","d":"D. Wave spread"}},{"num":113,"sample":"T3B02","correct":"D","question":"What term describes the number of times per second that an alternating current reverses direction?","answers":{"a":"A. Pulse rate","b":"B. Speed","c":"C. Wavelength","d":"D. Frequency"}},{"num":114,"sample":"T3B03","correct":"C","question":"What are the two components of a radio wave?","answers":{"a":"A. AC and DC","b":"B. Voltage and current","c":"C. Electric and magnetic fields","d":"D. Ionizing and non-ionizing radiation"}},{"num":115,"sample":"T3B04","correct":"A","question":"How fast does a radio wave travel through free space?","answers":{"a":"A. At the speed of light","b":"B. At the speed of sound","c":"C. Its speed is inversely proportional to its wavelength","d":"D. Its speed increases as the frequency increases"}},{"num":116,"sample":"T3B05","correct":"B","question":"How does the wavelength of a radio wave relate to its frequency?","answers":{"a":"A. The wavelength gets longer as the frequency increases","b":"B. The wavelength gets shorter as the frequency increases","c":"C. There is no relationship between wavelength and frequency","d":"D. The wavelength depends on the bandwidth of the signal"}},{"num":117,"sample":"T3B06","correct":"D","question":"What is the formula for converting frequency to wavelength in meters?","answers":{"a":"A. Wavelength in meters equals frequency in hertz multiplied by 300","b":"B. Wavelength in meters equals frequency in hertz divided by 300","c":"C. Wavelength in meters equals frequency in megahertz divided by 300","d":"D. Wavelength in meters equals 300 divided by frequency in megahertz"}},{"num":118,"sample":"T3B07","correct":"A","question":"What property of radio waves is often used to identify the different frequency bands?","answers":{"a":"A. The approximate wavelength","b":"B. The magnetic intensity of waves","c":"C. The time it takes for waves to travel one mile","d":"D. The voltage standing wave ratio of waves"}},{"num":119,"sample":"T3B08","correct":"B","question":"What are the frequency limits of the VHF spectrum?","answers":{"a":"A. 30 to 300 kHz","b":"B. 30 to 300 MHz","c":"C. 300 to 3000 kHz","d":"D. 300 to 3000 MHz"}},{"num":120,"sample":"T3B09","correct":"D","question":"What are the frequency limits of the UHF spectrum?","answers":{"a":"A. 30 to 300 kHz","b":"B. 30 to 300 MHz","c":"C. 300 to 3000 kHz","d":"D. 300 to 3000 MHz"}},{"num":121,"sample":"T3B10","correct":"C","question":"What frequency range is referred to as HF?","answers":{"a":"A. 300 to 3000 MHz","b":"B. 30 to 300 MHz","c":"C. 3 to 30 MHz","d":"D. 300 to 3000 kHz"}},{"num":122,"sample":"T3B11","correct":"B","question":"What is the approximate velocity of a radio wave as it travels through free space?","answers":{"a":"A. 3000 kilometers per second","b":"B. 300,000,000 meters per second","c":"C. 300,000 miles per hour","d":"D. 186,000 miles per hour"}},{"num":123,"sample":"T3C01","correct":"C","question":"Why are \"direct\" (not via a repeater) UHF signals rarely heard from stations outside your local coverage area?","answers":{"a":"A. They are too weak to go very far","b":"B. FCC regulations prohibit them from going more than 50 miles","c":"C. UHF signals are usually not reflected by the ionosphere","d":"D. They collide with trees and shrubbery and fade out"}},{"num":124,"sample":"T3C02","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following might be happening when VHF signals are being received from long distances?","answers":{"a":"A. Signals are being reflected from outer space","b":"B. Signals are arriving by sub-surface ducting","c":"C. Signals are being reflected by lightning storms in your area","d":"D. Signals are being refracted from a sporadic E layer"}},{"num":125,"sample":"T3C03","correct":"B","question":"What is a characteristic of VHF signals received via auroral reflection?","answers":{"a":"A. Signals from distances of 10,000 or more miles are common","b":"B. The signals exhibit rapid fluctuations of strength and often sound distorted","c":"C. These types of signals occur only during winter nighttime hours","d":"D. These types of signals are generally strongest when your antenna is aimed to the south (for stations in the Northern Hemisphere)"}},{"num":126,"sample":"T3C04","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following propagation types is most commonly associated with occasional strong over-the-horizon signals on the 10, 6, and 2 meter bands?","answers":{"a":"A. Backscatter","b":"B. Sporadic E","c":"C. D layer absorption","d":"D. Gray-line propagation"}},{"num":127,"sample":"T3C05","correct":"C","question":"What is meant by the term \"knife-edge\" propagation?","answers":{"a":"A. Signals are reflected back toward the originating station at acute angles","b":"B. Signals are sliced into several discrete beams and arrive via different paths","c":"C. Signals are partially refracted around solid objects exhibiting sharp edges","d":"D. Signals propagated close to the band edge exhibiting a sharp cutoff"}},{"num":128,"sample":"T3C06","correct":"A","question":"What mode is responsible for allowing over-the-horizon VHF and UHF communications to ranges of approximately 300 miles on a regular basis?","answers":{"a":"A. Tropospheric scatter","b":"B. D layer refraction","c":"C. F2 layer refraction","d":"D. Faraday rotation"}},{"num":129,"sample":"T3C07","correct":"B","question":"What band is best suited to communicating via meteor scatter?","answers":{"a":"A. 10 meters","b":"B. 6 meters","c":"C. 2 meters","d":"D. 70 cm"}},{"num":130,"sample":"T3C08","correct":"D","question":"What causes \"tropospheric ducting\"?","answers":{"a":"A. Discharges of lightning during electrical storms","b":"B. Sunspots and solar flares","c":"C. Updrafts from hurricanes and tornadoes","d":"D. Temperature inversions in the atmosphere"}},{"num":131,"sample":"T3C09","correct":"A","question":"What is generally the best time for long-distance 10 meter band propagation?","answers":{"a":"A. During daylight hours","b":"B. During nighttime hours","c":"C. When there are coronal mass ejections","d":"D. Whenever the solar flux is low"}},{"num":132,"sample":"T3C10","correct":"A","question":"What is the radio horizon?","answers":{"a":"A. The distance at which radio signals between two points are effectively blocked by the curvature of the Earth","b":"B. The distance from the ground to a horizontally mounted antenna","c":"C. The farthest point you can see when standing at the base of your antenna tower","d":"D. The shortest distance between two points on the Earth's surface"}},{"num":133,"sample":"T3C11","correct":"C","question":"Why do VHF and UHF radio signals usually travel somewhat farther than the visual line of sight distance between two stations?","answers":{"a":"A. Radio signals move somewhat faster than the speed of light","b":"B. Radio waves are not blocked by dust particles","c":"C. The Earth seems less curved to radio waves than to light","d":"D. Radio waves are blocked by dust particles"}},{"num":134,"sample":"T4A01","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following is true concerning the microphone connectors on amateur transceivers?","answers":{"a":"A. All transceivers use the same microphone connector type","b":"B. Some connectors include push-to-talk and voltages for powering the microphone","c":"C. All transceivers using the same connector type are wired identically","d":"D. Un-keyed connectors allow any microphone to be connected"}},{"num":135,"sample":"T4A02","correct":"C","question":"What could be used in place of a regular speaker to help you copy signals in a noisy area?","answers":{"a":"A. A video display","b":"B. A low pass filter","c":"C. A set of headphones","d":"D. A boom microphone"}},{"num":136,"sample":"T4A03","correct":"A","question":"Which is a good reason to use a regulated power supply for communications equipment?","answers":{"a":"A. It prevents voltage fluctuations from reaching sensitive circuits","b":"B. A regulated power supply has FCC approval","c":"C. A fuse or circuit breaker regulates the power","d":"D. Power consumption is independent of load"}},{"num":137,"sample":"T4A04","correct":"A","question":"Where must a filter be installed to reduce harmonic emissions?","answers":{"a":"A. Between the transmitter and the antenna","b":"B. Between the receiver and the transmitter","c":"C. At the station power supply","d":"D. At the microphone"}},{"num":138,"sample":"T4A05","correct":"D","question":"What type of filter should be connected to a TV receiver as the first step in trying to prevent RF overload from a nearby 2 meter transmitter?","answers":{"a":"A. Low-pass filter","b":"B. High-pass filter","c":"C. Band-pass filter","d":"D. Band-reject filter"}},{"num":139,"sample":"T4A06","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following would be connected between a transceiver and computer in a packet radio station?","answers":{"a":"A. Transmatch","b":"B. Mixer","c":"C. Terminal node controller","d":"D. Antenna"}},{"num":140,"sample":"T4A07","correct":"C","question":"How is the computer's sound card used when conducting digital communications using a computer?","answers":{"a":"A. The sound card communicates between the computer CPU and the video display","b":"B. The sound card records the audio frequency for video display","c":"C. The sound card provides audio to the microphone input and converts received audio to digital form","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":141,"sample":"T4A08","correct":"D","question":"Which type of conductor is best to use for RF grounding?","answers":{"a":"A. Round stranded wire","b":"B. Round copper-clad steel wire","c":"C. Twisted-pair cable","d":"D. Flat strap"}},{"num":142,"sample":"T4A09","correct":"D","question":"Which would you use to reduce RF current flowing on the shield of an audio cable?","answers":{"a":"A. Band-pass filter","b":"B. Low-pass filter","c":"C. Preamplifier","d":"D. Ferrite choke"}},{"num":143,"sample":"T4A10","correct":"B","question":"What is the source of a high-pitched whine that varies with engine speed in a mobile transceiver's receive audio?","answers":{"a":"A. The ignition system","b":"B. The alternator","c":"C. The electric fuel pump","d":"D. Anti-lock braking system controllers"}},{"num":144,"sample":"T4A11","correct":"A","question":"Where should a mobile transceiver's power negative connection be made?","answers":{"a":"A. At the battery or engine block ground strap","b":"B. At the antenna mount","c":"C. To any metal part of the vehicle","d":"D. Through the transceiver's mounting bracket"}},{"num":145,"sample":"T4B01","correct":"B","question":"What may happen if a transmitter is operated with the microphone gain set too high?","answers":{"a":"A. The output power might be too high","b":"B. The output signal might become distorted","c":"C. The frequency might vary","d":"D. The SWR might increase"}},{"num":146,"sample":"T4B02","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following can be used to enter the operating frequency on a modern transceiver?","answers":{"a":"A. The keypad or VFO knob","b":"B. The CTCSS or DTMF encoder","c":"C. The Automatic Frequency Control","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":147,"sample":"T4B03","correct":"D","question":"What is the purpose of the squelch control on a transceiver?","answers":{"a":"A. To set the highest level of volume desired","b":"B. To set the transmitter power level","c":"C. To adjust the automatic gain control","d":"D. To mute receiver output noise when no signal is being received"}},{"num":148,"sample":"T4B04","correct":"B","question":"What is a way to enable quick access to a favorite frequency on your transceiver?","answers":{"a":"A. Enable the CTCSS tones","b":"B. Store the frequency in a memory channel","c":"C. Disable the CTCSS tones","d":"D. Use the scan mode to select the desired frequency"}},{"num":149,"sample":"T4B05","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following would reduce ignition interference to a receiver?","answers":{"a":"A. Change frequency slightly","b":"B. Decrease the squelch setting","c":"C. Turn on the noise blanker","d":"D. Use the RIT control"}},{"num":150,"sample":"T4B06","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following controls could be used if the voice pitch of a single-sideband signal seems too high or low?","answers":{"a":"A. The AGC or limiter","b":"B. The bandwidth selection","c":"C. The tone squelch","d":"D. The receiver RIT or clarifier"}},{"num":151,"sample":"T4B07","correct":"B","question":"What does the term \"RIT\" mean?","answers":{"a":"A. Receiver Input Tone","b":"B. Receiver Incremental Tuning","c":"C. Rectifier Inverter Test","d":"D. Remote Input Transmitter"}},{"num":152,"sample":"T4B08","correct":"B","question":"What is the advantage of having multiple receive bandwidth choices on a multimode transceiver?","answers":{"a":"A. Permits monitoring several modes at once","b":"B. Permits noise or interference reduction by selecting a bandwidth matching the mode","c":"C. Increases the number of frequencies that can be stored in memory","d":"D. Increases the amount of offset between receive and transmit frequencies"}},{"num":153,"sample":"T4B09","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following is an appropriate receive filter to select in order to minimize noise and interference for SSB reception?","answers":{"a":"A. 500 Hz","b":"B. 1000 Hz","c":"C. 2400 Hz","d":"D. 5000 Hz"}},{"num":154,"sample":"T4B10","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following is an appropriate receive filter to select in order to minimize noise and interference for CW reception?","answers":{"a":"A. 500 Hz","b":"B. 1000 Hz","c":"C. 2400 Hz","d":"D. 5000 Hz"}},{"num":155,"sample":"T4B11","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following describes the common meaning of the term \"repeater offset\"?","answers":{"a":"A. The distance between the repeater's transmit and receive antennas","b":"B. The time delay before the repeater timer resets","c":"C. The difference between the repeater's transmit and receive frequencies","d":"D. The maximum frequency deviation permitted on the repeater's input signal"}},{"num":156,"sample":"T5A01","correct":"D","question":"Electrical current is measured in which of the following units?","answers":{"a":"A. Volts","b":"B. Watts","c":"C. Ohms","d":"D. Amperes"}},{"num":157,"sample":"T5A02","correct":"B","question":"Electrical power is measured in which of the following units?","answers":{"a":"A. Volts","b":"B. Watts","c":"C. Ohms","d":"D. Amperes"}},{"num":158,"sample":"T5A03","correct":"D","question":"What is the name for the flow of electrons in an electric circuit?","answers":{"a":"A. Voltage","b":"B. Resistance","c":"C. Capacitance","d":"D. Current"}},{"num":159,"sample":"T5A04","correct":"B","question":"What is the name for a current that flows only in one direction?","answers":{"a":"A. Alternating current","b":"B. Direct current","c":"C. Normal current","d":"D. Smooth current"}},{"num":160,"sample":"T5A05","correct":"A","question":"What is the electrical term for the electromotive force (EMF) that causes electron flow?","answers":{"a":"A. Voltage","b":"B. Ampere-hours","c":"C. Capacitance","d":"D. Inductance"}},{"num":161,"sample":"T5A06","correct":"A","question":"How much voltage does a mobile transceiver usually require?","answers":{"a":"A. About 12 volts","b":"B. About 30 volts","c":"C. About 120 volts","d":"D. About 240 volts"}},{"num":162,"sample":"T5A07","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following is a good electrical conductor?","answers":{"a":"A. Glass","b":"B. Wood","c":"C. Copper","d":"D. Rubber"}},{"num":163,"sample":"T5A08","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following is a good electrical insulator?","answers":{"a":"A. Copper","b":"B. Glass","c":"C. Aluminum","d":"D. Mercury"}},{"num":164,"sample":"T5A09","correct":"A","question":"What is the name for a current that reverses direction on a regular basis?","answers":{"a":"A. Alternating current","b":"B. Direct current","c":"C. Circular current","d":"D. Vertical current"}},{"num":165,"sample":"T5A10","correct":"C","question":"Which term describes the rate at which electrical energy is used?","answers":{"a":"A. Resistance","b":"B. Current","c":"C. Power","d":"D. Voltage"}},{"num":166,"sample":"T5A11","correct":"A","question":"What is the basic unit of electromotive force?","answers":{"a":"A. The volt","b":"B. The watt","c":"C. The ampere","d":"D. The ohm"}},{"num":167,"sample":"T5B01","correct":"C","question":"How many milliamperes is 1.5 amperes?","answers":{"a":"A. 15 milliamperes","b":"B. 150 milliamperes","c":"C. 1,500 milliamperes","d":"D. 15,000 milliamperes"}},{"num":168,"sample":"T5B02","correct":"A","question":"What is another way to specify a radio signal frequency of 1,500,000 hertz?","answers":{"a":"A. 1500 kHz","b":"B. 1500 MHz","c":"C. 15 GHz","d":"D. 150 kHz"}},{"num":169,"sample":"T5B03","correct":"C","question":"How many volts are equal to one kilovolt?","answers":{"a":"A. One one-thousandth of a volt","b":"B. One hundred volts","c":"C. One thousand volts","d":"D. One million volts"}},{"num":170,"sample":"T5B04","correct":"A","question":"How many volts are equal to one microvolt?","answers":{"a":"A. One one-millionth of a volt","b":"B. One million volts","c":"C. One thousand kilovolts","d":"D. One one-thousandth of a volt"}},{"num":171,"sample":"T5B05","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following is equivalent to 500 milliwatts?","answers":{"a":"A. 0.02 watts","b":"B. 0.5 watts","c":"C. 5 watts","d":"D. 50 watts"}},{"num":172,"sample":"T5B06","correct":"C","question":"If an ammeter calibrated in amperes is used to measure a 3000-milliampere current, what reading would it show?","answers":{"a":"A. 0.003 amperes","b":"B. 0.3 amperes","c":"C. 3 amperes","d":"D. 3,000,000 amperes"}},{"num":173,"sample":"T5B07","correct":"C","question":"If a frequency readout calibrated in megahertz shows a reading of 3.525 MHz, what would it show if it were calibrated in kilohertz?","answers":{"a":"A. 0.003525 kHz","b":"B. 35.25 kHz","c":"C. 3525 kHz","d":"D. 3,525,000 kHz"}},{"num":174,"sample":"T5B08","correct":"B","question":"How many microfarads are 1,000,000 picofarads?","answers":{"a":"A. 0.001 microfarads","b":"B. 1 microfarad","c":"C. 1000 microfarads","d":"D. 1,000,000,000 microfarads"}},{"num":175,"sample":"T5B09","correct":"B","question":"What is the approximate amount of change, measured in decibels (dB), of a power increase from 5 watts to 10 watts?","answers":{"a":"A. 2 dB","b":"B. 3 dB","c":"C. 5 dB","d":"D. 10 dB"}},{"num":176,"sample":"T5B10","correct":"C","question":"What is the approximate amount of change, measured in decibels (dB), of a power decrease from 12 watts to 3 watts?","answers":{"a":"A. 1 dB","b":"B. 3 dB","c":"C. 6 dB","d":"D. 9 dB"}},{"num":177,"sample":"T5B11","correct":"A","question":"What is the approximate amount of change, measured in decibels (dB), of a power increase from 20 watts to 200 watts?","answers":{"a":"A. 10 dB","b":"B. 12 dB","c":"C. 18 dB","d":"D. 28 dB"}},{"num":178,"sample":"T5C01","correct":"D","question":"What is the ability to store energy in an electric field called?","answers":{"a":"A. Inductance","b":"B. Resistance","c":"C. Tolerance","d":"D. Capacitance"}},{"num":179,"sample":"T5C02","correct":"A","question":"What is the basic unit of capacitance?","answers":{"a":"A. The farad","b":"B. The ohm","c":"C. The volt","d":"D. The henry"}},{"num":180,"sample":"T5C03","correct":"D","question":"What is the ability to store energy in a magnetic field called?","answers":{"a":"A. Admittance","b":"B. Capacitance","c":"C. Resistance","d":"D. Inductance"}},{"num":181,"sample":"T5C04","correct":"C","question":"What is the basic unit of inductance?","answers":{"a":"A. The coulomb","b":"B. The farad","c":"C. The henry","d":"D. The ohm"}},{"num":182,"sample":"T5C05","correct":"A","question":"What is the unit of frequency?","answers":{"a":"A. Hertz","b":"B. Henry","c":"C. Farad","d":"D. Tesla"}},{"num":183,"sample":"T5C06","correct":"C","question":"What is the abbreviation that refers to radio frequency signals of all types?","answers":{"a":"A. AF","b":"B. HF","c":"C. RF","d":"D. VHF"}},{"num":184,"sample":"T5C07","correct":"C","question":"What is a usual name for electromagnetic waves that travel through space?","answers":{"a":"A. Gravity waves","b":"B. Sound waves","c":"C. Radio waves","d":"D. Pressure waves"}},{"num":185,"sample":"T5C08","correct":"A","question":"What is the formula used to calculate electrical power in a DC circuit?","answers":{"a":"A. Power (P) equals voltage (E) multiplied by current (I)","b":"B. Power (P) equals voltage (E) divided by current (I)","c":"C. Power (P) equals voltage (E) minus current (I)","d":"D. Power (P) equals voltage (E) plus current (I)"}},{"num":186,"sample":"T5C09","correct":"A","question":"How much power is being used in a circuit when the applied voltage is 13.8 volts DC and the current is 10 amperes?","answers":{"a":"A. 138 watts","b":"B. 0.7 watts","c":"C. 23.8 watts","d":"D. 3.8 watts"}},{"num":187,"sample":"T5C10","correct":"B","question":"How much power is being used in a circuit when the applied voltage is 12 volts DC and the current is 2.5 amperes?","answers":{"a":"A. 4.8 watts","b":"B. 30 watts","c":"C. 14.5 watts","d":"D. 0.208 watts"}},{"num":188,"sample":"T5C11","correct":"B","question":"How many amperes are flowing in a circuit when the applied voltage is 12 volts DC and the load is 120 watts?","answers":{"a":"A. 0.1 amperes","b":"B. 10 amperes","c":"C. 12 amperes","d":"D. 132 amperes"}},{"num":189,"sample":"T5D01","correct":"B","question":"What formula is used to calculate current in a circuit?","answers":{"a":"A. Current (I) equals voltage (E) multiplied by resistance (R)","b":"B. Current (I) equals voltage (E) divided by resistance (R)","c":"C. Current (I) equals voltage (E) added to resistance (R)","d":"D. Current (I) equals voltage (E) minus resistance (R)"}},{"num":190,"sample":"T5D02","correct":"A","question":"What formula is used to calculate voltage in a circuit?","answers":{"a":"A. Voltage (E) equals current (I) multiplied by resistance (R)","b":"B. Voltage (E) equals current (I) divided by resistance (R)","c":"C. Voltage (E) equals current (I) added to resistance (R)","d":"D. Voltage (E) equals current (I) minus resistance (R)"}},{"num":191,"sample":"T5D03","correct":"B","question":"What formula is used to calculate resistance in a circuit?","answers":{"a":"A. Resistance (R) equals voltage (E) multiplied by current (I)","b":"B. Resistance (R) equals voltage (E) divided by current (I)","c":"C. Resistance (R) equals voltage (E) added to current (I)","d":"D. Resistance (R) equals voltage (E) minus current (I)"}},{"num":192,"sample":"T5D04","correct":"B","question":"What is the resistance of a circuit in which a current of 3 amperes flows through a resistor connected to 90 volts?","answers":{"a":"A. 3 ohms","b":"B. 30 ohms","c":"C. 93 ohms","d":"D. 270 ohms"}},{"num":193,"sample":"T5D05","correct":"C","question":"What is the resistance in a circuit for which the applied voltage is 12 volts and the current flow is 1.5 amperes?","answers":{"a":"A. 18 ohms","b":"B. 0.125 ohms","c":"C. 8 ohms","d":"D. 13.5 ohms"}},{"num":194,"sample":"T5D06","correct":"A","question":"What is the resistance of a circuit that draws 4 amperes from a 12-volt source?","answers":{"a":"A. 3 ohms","b":"B. 16 ohms","c":"C. 48 ohms","d":"D. 8 Ohms"}},{"num":195,"sample":"T5D07","correct":"D","question":"What is the current flow in a circuit with an applied voltage of 120 volts and a resistance of 80 ohms?","answers":{"a":"A. 9600 amperes","b":"B. 200 amperes","c":"C. 0.667 amperes","d":"D. 1.5 amperes"}},{"num":196,"sample":"T5D08","correct":"C","question":"What is the current flowing through a 100-ohm resistor connected across 200 volts?","answers":{"a":"A. 20,000 amperes","b":"B. 0.5 amperes","c":"C. 2 amperes","d":"D. 100 amperes"}},{"num":197,"sample":"T5D09","correct":"C","question":"What is the current flowing through a 24-ohm resistor connected across 240 volts?","answers":{"a":"A. 24,000 amperes","b":"B. 0.1 amperes","c":"C. 10 amperes","d":"D. 216 amperes"}},{"num":198,"sample":"T5D10","correct":"A","question":"What is the voltage across a 2-ohm resistor if a current of 0.5 amperes flows through it?","answers":{"a":"A. 1 volt","b":"B. 0.25 volts","c":"C. 2.5 volts","d":"D. 1.5 volts"}},{"num":199,"sample":"T5D11","correct":"B","question":"What is the voltage across a 10-ohm resistor if a current of 1 ampere flows through it?","answers":{"a":"A. 1 volt","b":"B. 10 volts","c":"C. 11 volts","d":"D. 9 volts"}},{"num":200,"sample":"T5D12","correct":"D","question":"What is the voltage across a 10-ohm resistor if a current of 2 amperes flows through it?","answers":{"a":"A. 8 volts","b":"B. 0.2 volts","c":"C. 12 volts","d":"D. 20 volts"}},{"num":201,"sample":"T6A01","correct":"B","question":"What electrical component is used to oppose the flow of current in a DC circuit?","answers":{"a":"A. Inductor","b":"B. Resistor","c":"C. Voltmeter","d":"D. Transformer"}},{"num":202,"sample":"T6A02","correct":"C","question":"What type of component is often used as an adjustable volume control?","answers":{"a":"A. Fixed resistor","b":"B. Power resistor","c":"C. Potentiometer","d":"D. Transformer"}},{"num":203,"sample":"T6A03","correct":"B","question":"What electrical parameter is controlled by a potentiometer?","answers":{"a":"A. Inductance","b":"B. Resistance","c":"C. Capacitance","d":"D. Field strength"}},{"num":204,"sample":"T6A04","correct":"B","question":"What electrical component stores energy in an electric field?","answers":{"a":"A. Resistor","b":"B. Capacitor","c":"C. Inductor","d":"D. Diode"}},{"num":205,"sample":"T6A05","correct":"D","question":"What type of electrical component consists of two or more conductive surfaces separated by an insulator?","answers":{"a":"A. Resistor","b":"B. Potentiometer","c":"C. Oscillator","d":"D. Capacitor"}},{"num":206,"sample":"T6A06","correct":"C","question":"What type of electrical component stores energy in a magnetic field?","answers":{"a":"A. Resistor","b":"B. Capacitor","c":"C. Inductor","d":"D. Diode"}},{"num":207,"sample":"T6A07","correct":"D","question":"What electrical component is usually composed of a coil of wire?","answers":{"a":"A. Switch","b":"B. Capacitor","c":"C. Diode","d":"D. Inductor"}},{"num":208,"sample":"T6A08","correct":"B","question":"What electrical component is used to connect or disconnect electrical circuits?","answers":{"a":"A. Zener Diode","b":"B. Switch","c":"C. Inductor","d":"D. Variable resistor"}},{"num":209,"sample":"T6A09","correct":"A","question":"What electrical component is used to protect other circuit components from current overloads?","answers":{"a":"A. Fuse","b":"B. Capacitor","c":"C. Shield","d":"D. Inductor"}},{"num":210,"sample":"T6A10","correct":"B","question":"What is the nominal voltage of a fully charged nickel-cadmium cell?","answers":{"a":"A. 1.0 volts","b":"B. 1.2 volts","c":"C. 1.5 volts","d":"D. 2.2 volts"}},{"num":211,"sample":"T6A11","correct":"B","question":"Which battery type is not rechargeable?","answers":{"a":"A. Nickel-cadmium","b":"B. Carbon-zinc","c":"C. Lead-acid","d":"D. Lithium-ion"}},{"num":212,"sample":"T6B01","correct":"D","question":"What class of electronic components is capable of using a voltage or current signal to control current flow?","answers":{"a":"A. Capacitors","b":"B. Inductors","c":"C. Resistors","d":"D. Transistors"}},{"num":213,"sample":"T6B02","correct":"C","question":"What electronic component allows current to flow in only one direction?","answers":{"a":"A. Resistor","b":"B. Fuse","c":"C. Diode","d":"D. Driven Element"}},{"num":214,"sample":"T6B03","correct":"C","question":"Which of these components can be used as an electronic switch or amplifier?","answers":{"a":"A. Oscillator","b":"B. Potentiometer","c":"C. Transistor","d":"D. Voltmeter"}},{"num":215,"sample":"T6B04","correct":"B","question":"Which of these components is made of three layers of semiconductor material?","answers":{"a":"A. Alternator","b":"B. Bipolar junction transistor","c":"C. Triode","d":"D. Pentagrid converter"}},{"num":216,"sample":"T6B05","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following electronic components can amplify signals?","answers":{"a":"A. Transistor","b":"B. Variable resistor","c":"C. Electrolytic capacitor","d":"D. Multi-cell battery"}},{"num":217,"sample":"T6B06","correct":"B","question":"How is a semiconductor diode's cathode lead usually identified?","answers":{"a":"A. With the word \"cathode\"","b":"B. With a stripe","c":"C. With the letter \"C\"","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":218,"sample":"T6B07","correct":"B","question":"What does the abbreviation \"LED\" stand for?","answers":{"a":"A. Low Emission Diode","b":"B. Light Emitting Diode","c":"C. Liquid Emission Detector","d":"D. Long Echo Delay"}},{"num":219,"sample":"T6B08","correct":"A","question":"What does the abbreviation \"FET\" stand for?","answers":{"a":"A. Field Effect Transistor","b":"B. Fast Electron Transistor","c":"C. Free Electron Transition","d":"D. Field Emission Thickness"}},{"num":220,"sample":"T6B09","correct":"C","question":"What are the names of the two electrodes of a diode?","answers":{"a":"A. Plus and minus","b":"B. Source and drain","c":"C. Anode and cathode","d":"D. Gate and base"}},{"num":221,"sample":"T6B10","correct":"A","question":"Which semiconductor component has an emitter electrode?","answers":{"a":"A. Bipolar transistor","b":"B. Field effect transistor","c":"C. Silicon diode","d":"D. Bridge rectifier"}},{"num":222,"sample":"T6B11","correct":"B","question":"Which semiconductor component has a gate electrode?","answers":{"a":"A. Bipolar transistor","b":"B. Field effect transistor","c":"C. Silicon diode","d":"D. Bridge rectifier"}},{"num":223,"sample":"T6B12","correct":"A","question":"What is the term that describes a transistor's ability to amplify a signal?","answers":{"a":"A. Gain","b":"B. Forward resistance","c":"C. Forward voltage drop","d":"D. On resistance"}},{"num":224,"sample":"T6C01","correct":"C","question":"What is the name for standardized representations of components in an electrical wiring diagram?","answers":{"a":"A. Electrical depictions","b":"B. Grey sketch","c":"C. Schematic symbols","d":"D. Component callouts"}},{"num":225,"sample":"T6C02","correct":"A","question":"What is component 1 in figure T1?","answers":{"a":"A. Resistor","b":"B. Transistor","c":"C. Battery","d":"D. Connector"}},{"num":226,"sample":"T6C03","correct":"B","question":"What is component 2 in figure T1?","answers":{"a":"A. Resistor","b":"B. Transistor","c":"C. Indicator lamp","d":"D. Connector"}},{"num":227,"sample":"T6C04","correct":"C","question":"What is component 3 in figure T1?","answers":{"a":"A. Resistor","b":"B. Transistor","c":"C. Lamp","d":"D. Ground symbol"}},{"num":228,"sample":"T6C05","correct":"C","question":"What is component 4 in figure T1?","answers":{"a":"A. Resistor","b":"B. Transistor","c":"C. Battery","d":"D. Ground symbol"}},{"num":229,"sample":"T6C06","correct":"B","question":"What is component 6 in figure T2?","answers":{"a":"A. Resistor","b":"B. Capacitor","c":"C. Regulator IC","d":"D. Transistor"}},{"num":230,"sample":"T6C07","correct":"D","question":"What is component 8 in figure T2?","answers":{"a":"A. Resistor","b":"B. Inductor","c":"C. Regulator IC","d":"D. Light emitting diode"}},{"num":231,"sample":"T6C08","correct":"C","question":"What is component 9 in figure T2?","answers":{"a":"A. Variable capacitor","b":"B. Variable inductor","c":"C. Variable resistor","d":"D. Variable transformer"}},{"num":232,"sample":"T6C09","correct":"D","question":"What is component 4 in figure T2?","answers":{"a":"A. Variable inductor","b":"B. Double-pole switch","c":"C. Potentiometer","d":"D. Transformer"}},{"num":233,"sample":"T6C10","correct":"D","question":"What is component 3 in figure T3?","answers":{"a":"A. Connector","b":"B. Meter","c":"C. Variable capacitor","d":"D. Variable inductor"}},{"num":234,"sample":"T6C11","correct":"A","question":"What is component 4 in figure T3?","answers":{"a":"A. Antenna","b":"B. Transmitter","c":"C. Dummy load","d":"D. Ground"}},{"num":235,"sample":"T6C12","correct":"A","question":"What do the symbols on an electrical circuit schematic diagram represent?","answers":{"a":"A. Electrical components","b":"B. Logic states","c":"C. Digital codes","d":"D. Traffic nodes"}},{"num":236,"sample":"T6C13","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following is accurately represented in electrical circuit schematic diagrams?","answers":{"a":"A. Wire lengths","b":"B. Physical appearance of components","c":"C. The way components are interconnected","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":237,"sample":"T6D01","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following devices or circuits changes an alternating current into a varying direct current signal?","answers":{"a":"A. Transformer","b":"B. Rectifier","c":"C. Amplifier","d":"D. Reflector"}},{"num":238,"sample":"T6D02","correct":"A","question":"What best describes a relay?","answers":{"a":"A. A switch controlled by an electromagnet","b":"B. A current controlled amplifier","c":"C. An optical sensor","d":"D. A pass transistor"}},{"num":239,"sample":"T6D03","correct":"A","question":"What type of switch is represented by item 3 in figure T2?","answers":{"a":"A. Single-pole single-throw","b":"B. Single-pole double-throw","c":"C. Double-pole single-throw","d":"D. Double-pole double-throw"}},{"num":240,"sample":"T6D04","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following can be used to display signal strength on a numeric scale?","answers":{"a":"A. Potentiometer","b":"B. Transistor","c":"C. Meter","d":"D. Relay"}},{"num":241,"sample":"T6D05","correct":"A","question":"What type of circuit controls the amount of voltage from a power supply?","answers":{"a":"A. Regulator","b":"B. Oscillator","c":"C. Filter","d":"D. Phase inverter"}},{"num":242,"sample":"T6D06","correct":"B","question":"What component is commonly used to change 120V AC house current to a lower AC voltage for other uses?","answers":{"a":"A. Variable capacitor","b":"B. Transformer","c":"C. Transistor","d":"D. Diode"}},{"num":243,"sample":"T6D07","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following is commonly used as a visual indicator?","answers":{"a":"A. LED","b":"B. FET","c":"C. Zener diode","d":"D. Bipolar transistor"}},{"num":244,"sample":"T6D08","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following is used together with an inductor to make a tuned circuit?","answers":{"a":"A. Resistor","b":"B. Zener diode","c":"C. Potentiometer","d":"D. Capacitor"}},{"num":245,"sample":"T6D09","correct":"C","question":"What is the name of a device that combines several semiconductors and other components into one package?","answers":{"a":"A. Transducer","b":"B. Multi-pole relay","c":"C. Integrated circuit","d":"D. Transformer"}},{"num":246,"sample":"T6D10","correct":"C","question":"What is the function of component 2 in Figure T1?","answers":{"a":"A. Give off light when current flows through it","b":"B. Supply electrical energy","c":"C. Control the flow of current","d":"D. Convert electrical energy into radio waves"}},{"num":247,"sample":"T6D11","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following is a common use of coaxial cable?","answers":{"a":"A. Carry dc power from a vehicle battery to a mobile radio","b":"B. Carry RF signals between a radio and antenna","c":"C. Secure masts, tubing, and other cylindrical objects on towers","d":"D. Connect data signals from a TNC to a computer"}},{"num":248,"sample":"T7A01","correct":"C","question":"What is the function of a product detector?","answers":{"a":"A. Detect phase modulated signals","b":"B. Demodulate FM signals","c":"C. Detect CW and SSB signals","d":"D. Combine speech and RF signals"}},{"num":249,"sample":"T7A02","correct":"C","question":"What type of receiver is shown in Figure T6?","answers":{"a":"A. Direct conversion","b":"B. Super-regenerative","c":"C. Single-conversion superheterodyne","d":"D. Dual-conversion superheterodyne"}},{"num":250,"sample":"T7A03","correct":"C","question":"What is the function of a mixer in a superheterodyne receiver?","answers":{"a":"A. To reject signals outside of the desired passband","b":"B. To combine signals from several stations together","c":"C. To shift the incoming signal to an intermediate frequency","d":"D. To connect the receiver with an auxiliary device, such as a TNC"}},{"num":251,"sample":"T7A04","correct":"D","question":"What circuit is pictured in Figure T7, if block 1 is a frequency discriminator?","answers":{"a":"A. A double-conversion receiver","b":"B. A regenerative receiver","c":"C. A superheterodyne receiver","d":"D. An FM receiver"}},{"num":252,"sample":"T7A05","correct":"D","question":"What is the function of block 1 if figure T4 is a simple CW transmitter?","answers":{"a":"A. Reactance modulator","b":"B. Product detector","c":"C. Low-pass filter","d":"D. Oscillator"}},{"num":253,"sample":"T7A06","correct":"C","question":"What device takes the output of a low-powered 28 MHz SSB exciter and produces a 222 MHz output signal?","answers":{"a":"A. High-pass filter","b":"B. Low-pass filter","c":"C. Transverter","d":"D. Phase converter"}},{"num":254,"sample":"T7A07","correct":"B","question":"If figure T5 represents a transceiver in which block 1 is the transmitter portion and block 3 is the receiver portion, what is the function of block 2?","answers":{"a":"A. A balanced modulator","b":"B. A transmit-receive switch","c":"C. A power amplifier","d":"D. A high-pass filter"}},{"num":255,"sample":"T7A08","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following circuits combines a speech signal and an RF carrier?","answers":{"a":"A. Beat frequency oscillator","b":"B. Discriminator","c":"C. Modulator","d":"D. Noise blanker"}},{"num":256,"sample":"T7A09","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following devices is most useful for VHF weak-signal communication?","answers":{"a":"A. A quarter-wave vertical antenna","b":"B. A multi-mode VHF transceiver","c":"C. An omni-directional antenna","d":"D. A mobile VHF FM transceiver"}},{"num":257,"sample":"T7A10","correct":"B","question":"What device increases the low-power output from a handheld transceiver?","answers":{"a":"A. A voltage divider","b":"B. An RF power amplifier","c":"C. An impedance network","d":"D. A voltage regulator"}},{"num":258,"sample":"T7A11","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following circuits demodulates FM signals?","answers":{"a":"A. Limiter","b":"B. Discriminator","c":"C. Product detector","d":"D. Phase inverter"}},{"num":259,"sample":"T7A12","correct":"C","question":"Which term describes the ability of a receiver to discriminate between multiple signals?","answers":{"a":"A. Tuning rate","b":"B. Sensitivity","c":"C. Selectivity","d":"D. Noise floor"}},{"num":260,"sample":"T7A13","correct":"A","question":"Where is an RF preamplifier installed?","answers":{"a":"A. Between the antenna and receiver","b":"B. At the output of the transmitter's power amplifier","c":"C. Between a transmitter and antenna tuner","d":"D. At the receiver's audio output"}},{"num":261,"sample":"T7B01","correct":"D","question":"What can you do if you are told your FM handheld or mobile transceiver is over deviating?","answers":{"a":"A. Talk louder into the microphone","b":"B. Let the transceiver cool off","c":"C. Change to a higher power level","d":"D. Talk farther away from the microphone"}},{"num":262,"sample":"T7B02","correct":"C","question":"What is meant by fundamental overload in reference to a receiver?","answers":{"a":"A. Too much voltage from the power supply","b":"B. Too much current from the power supply","c":"C. Interference caused by very strong signals","d":"D. Interference caused by turning the volume up too high"}},{"num":263,"sample":"T7B03","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following may be a cause of radio frequency interference?","answers":{"a":"A. Fundamental overload","b":"B. Harmonics","c":"C. Spurious emissions","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":264,"sample":"T7B04","correct":"B","question":"What is the most likely cause of interference to a non-cordless telephone from a nearby transmitter?","answers":{"a":"A. Harmonics from the transmitter","b":"B. The telephone is inadvertently acting as a radio receiver","c":"C. Poor station grounding","d":"D. Improper transmitter adjustment"}},{"num":265,"sample":"T7B05","correct":"C","question":"What is a logical first step when attempting to cure a radio frequency interference problem in a nearby telephone?","answers":{"a":"A. Install a low-pass filter at the transmitter","b":"B. Install a high-pass filter at the transmitter","c":"C. Install an RF filter at the telephone","d":"D. Improve station grounding"}},{"num":266,"sample":"T7B06","correct":"A","question":"What should you do first if someone tells you that your station's transmissions are interfering with their radio or TV reception?","answers":{"a":"A. Make sure that your station is functioning properly and that it does not cause interference to your own television","b":"B. Immediately turn off your transmitter and contact the nearest FCC office for assistance","c":"C. Tell them that your license gives you the right to transmit and nothing can be done to reduce the interference","d":"D. Continue operating normally because your equipment cannot possibly cause any interference"}},{"num":267,"sample":"T7B07","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following may be useful in correcting a radio frequency interference problem?","answers":{"a":"A. Snap-on ferrite chokes","b":"B. Low-pass and high-pass filters","c":"C. Band-reject and band-pass filters","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":268,"sample":"T7B08","correct":"D","question":"What should you do if a \"Part 15\" device in your neighbor's home is causing harmful interference to your amateur station?","answers":{"a":"A. Work with your neighbor to identify the offending device","b":"B. Politely inform your neighbor about the rules that require him to stop using the device if it causes interference","c":"C. Check your station and make sure it meets the standards of good amateur practice","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":269,"sample":"T7B09","correct":"D","question":"What could be happening if another operator reports a variable high-pitched whine on the audio from your mobile transmitter?","answers":{"a":"A. Your microphone is picking up noise from an open window","b":"B. You have the volume on your receiver set too high","c":"C. You need to adjust your squelch control","d":"D. Noise on the vehicle's electrical system is being transmitted along with your speech audio"}},{"num":270,"sample":"T7B10","correct":"D","question":"What might be the problem if you receive a report that your audio signal through the repeater is distorted or unintelligible?","answers":{"a":"A. Your transmitter may be slightly off frequency","b":"B. Your batteries may be running low","c":"C. You could be in a bad location","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":271,"sample":"T7B11","correct":"C","question":"What is a symptom of RF feedback in a transmitter or transceiver?","answers":{"a":"A. Excessive SWR at the antenna connection","b":"B. The transmitter will not stay on the desired frequency","c":"C. Reports of garbled, distorted, or unintelligible transmissions","d":"D. Frequent blowing of power supply fuses"}},{"num":272,"sample":"T7B12","correct":"C","question":"What does the acronym \"BER\" mean when applied to digital communications systems?","answers":{"a":"A. Baud Enhancement Recovery","b":"B. Baud Error Removal","c":"C. Bit Error Rate","d":"D. Bit Exponent Resource"}},{"num":273,"sample":"T7C01","correct":"A","question":"What is the primary purpose of a dummy load?","answers":{"a":"A. To prevent the radiation of signals when making tests","b":"B. To prevent over-modulation of your transmitter","c":"C. To improve the radiation from your antenna","d":"D. To improve the signal to noise ratio of your receiver"}},{"num":274,"sample":"T7C02","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following instruments can be used to determine if an antenna is resonant at the desired operating frequency?","answers":{"a":"A. A VTVM","b":"B. An antenna analyzer","c":"C. A \"Q\" meter","d":"D. A frequency counter"}},{"num":275,"sample":"T7C03","correct":"A","question":"What, in general terms, is standing wave ratio (SWR)?","answers":{"a":"A. A measure of how well a load is matched to a transmission line","b":"B. The ratio of high to low impedance in a feedline","c":"C. The transmitter efficiency ratio","d":"D. An indication of the quality of your station's ground connection"}},{"num":276,"sample":"T7C04","correct":"C","question":"What reading on an SWR meter indicates a perfect impedance match between the antenna and the feedline?","answers":{"a":"A. 2 to 1","b":"B. 1 to 3","c":"C. 1 to 1","d":"D. 10 to 1"}},{"num":277,"sample":"T7C05","correct":"A","question":"What is the approximate SWR value above which the protection circuits in most solid-state transmitters begin to reduce transmitter power?","answers":{"a":"A. 2 to 1","b":"B. 1 to 2","c":"C. 6 to 1","d":"D. 10 to 1"}},{"num":278,"sample":"T7C06","correct":"D","question":"What does an SWR reading of 4:1 mean?","answers":{"a":"A. An antenna loss of 4 dB","b":"B. A good impedance match","c":"C. An antenna gain of 4","d":"D. An impedance mismatch"}},{"num":279,"sample":"T7C07","correct":"C","question":"What happens to power lost in a feedline?","answers":{"a":"A. It increases the SWR","b":"B. It comes back into your transmitter and could cause damage","c":"C. It is converted into heat","d":"D. It can cause distortion of your signal"}},{"num":280,"sample":"T7C08","correct":"D","question":"What instrument other than an SWR meter could you use to determine if a feedline and antenna are properly matched?","answers":{"a":"A. Voltmeter","b":"B. Ohmmeter","c":"C. Iambic pentameter","d":"D. Directional wattmeter"}},{"num":281,"sample":"T7C09","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause for failure of coaxial cables?","answers":{"a":"A. Moisture contamination","b":"B. Gamma rays","c":"C. The velocity factor exceeds 1.0","d":"D. Overloading"}},{"num":282,"sample":"T7C10","correct":"D","question":"Why should the outer jacket of coaxial cable be resistant to ultraviolet light?","answers":{"a":"A. Ultraviolet resistant jackets prevent harmonic radiation","b":"B. Ultraviolet light can increase losses in the cable's jacket","c":"C. Ultraviolet and RF signals can mix together, causing interference","d":"D. Ultraviolet light can damage the jacket and allow water to enter the cable"}},{"num":283,"sample":"T7C11","correct":"C","question":"What is a disadvantage of \"air core\" coaxial cable when compared to foam or solid dielectric types?","answers":{"a":"A. It has more loss per foot","b":"B. It cannot be used for VHF or UHF antennas","c":"C. It requires special techniques to prevent water absorption","d":"D. It cannot be used at below freezing temperatures"}},{"num":284,"sample":"T7D01","correct":"B","question":"Which instrument would you use to measure electric potential or electromotive force?","answers":{"a":"A. An ammeter","b":"B. A voltmeter","c":"C. A wavemeter","d":"D. An ohmmeter"}},{"num":285,"sample":"T7D02","correct":"B","question":"What is the correct way to connect a voltmeter to a circuit?","answers":{"a":"A. In series with the circuit","b":"B. In parallel with the circuit","c":"C. In quadrature with the circuit","d":"D. In phase with the circuit"}},{"num":286,"sample":"T7D03","correct":"A","question":"How is an ammeter usually connected to a circuit?","answers":{"a":"A. In series with the circuit","b":"B. In parallel with the circuit","c":"C. In quadrature with the circuit","d":"D. In phase with the circuit"}},{"num":287,"sample":"T7D04","correct":"D","question":"Which instrument is used to measure electric current?","answers":{"a":"A. An ohmmeter","b":"B. A wavemeter","c":"C. A voltmeter","d":"D. An ammeter"}},{"num":288,"sample":"T7D05","correct":"D","question":"What instrument is used to measure resistance?","answers":{"a":"A. An oscilloscope","b":"B. A spectrum analyzer","c":"C. A noise bridge","d":"D. An ohmmeter"}},{"num":289,"sample":"T7D06","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following might damage a multimeter?","answers":{"a":"A. Measuring a voltage too small for the chosen scale","b":"B. Leaving the meter in the milliamps position overnight","c":"C. Attempting to measure voltage when using the resistance setting","d":"D. Not allowing it to warm up properly"}},{"num":290,"sample":"T7D07","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following measurements are commonly made using a multimeter?","answers":{"a":"A. SWR and RF power","b":"B. Signal strength and noise","c":"C. Impedance and reactance","d":"D. Voltage and resistance"}},{"num":291,"sample":"T7D08","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following types of solder is best for radio and electronic use?","answers":{"a":"A. Acid-core solder","b":"B. Silver solder","c":"C. Rosin-core solder","d":"D. Aluminum solder"}},{"num":292,"sample":"T7D09","correct":"C","question":"What is the characteristic appearance of a \"cold\" solder joint?","answers":{"a":"A. Dark black spots","b":"B. A bright or shiny surface","c":"C. A grainy or dull surface","d":"D. A greenish tint"}},{"num":293,"sample":"T7D10","correct":"B","question":"What is probably happening when an ohmmeter, connected across a circuit, initially indicates a low resistance and then shows increasing resistance with time?","answers":{"a":"A. The ohmmeter is defective","b":"B. The circuit contains a large capacitor","c":"C. The circuit contains a large inductor","d":"D. The circuit is a relaxation oscillator"}},{"num":294,"sample":"T7D11","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following precautions should be taken when measuring circuit resistance with an ohmmeter?","answers":{"a":"A. Ensure that the applied voltages are correct","b":"B. Ensure that the circuit is not powered","c":"C. Ensure that the circuit is grounded","d":"D. Ensure that the circuit is operating at the correct frequency"}},{"num":295,"sample":"T8A01","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following is a form of amplitude modulation?","answers":{"a":"A. Spread-spectrum","b":"B. Packet radio","c":"C. Single sideband","d":"D. Phase shift keying"}},{"num":296,"sample":"T8A02","correct":"A","question":"What type of modulation is most commonly used for VHF packet radio transmissions?","answers":{"a":"A. FM","b":"B. SSB","c":"C. AM","d":"D. Spread Spectrum"}},{"num":297,"sample":"T8A03","correct":"C","question":"Which type of voice modulation is most often used for long-distance or weak signal contacts on the VHF and UHF bands?","answers":{"a":"A. FM","b":"B. AM","c":"C. SSB","d":"D. PM"}},{"num":298,"sample":"T8A04","correct":"D","question":"Which type of modulation is most commonly used for VHF and UHF voice repeaters?","answers":{"a":"A. AM","b":"B. SSB","c":"C. PSK","d":"D. FM"}},{"num":299,"sample":"T8A05","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following types of emission has the narrowest bandwidth?","answers":{"a":"A. FM voice","b":"B. SSB voice","c":"C. CW","d":"D. Slow-scan TV"}},{"num":300,"sample":"T8A06","correct":"A","question":"Which sideband is normally used for 10 meter HF, VHF and UHF single-sideband communications?","answers":{"a":"A. Upper sideband","b":"B. Lower sideband","c":"C. Suppressed sideband","d":"D. Inverted sideband"}},{"num":301,"sample":"T8A07","correct":"C","question":"What is the primary advantage of single sideband over FM for voice transmissions?","answers":{"a":"A. SSB signals are easier to tune","b":"B. SSB signals are less susceptible to interference","c":"C. SSB signals have narrower bandwidth","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":302,"sample":"T8A08","correct":"B","question":"What is the approximate bandwidth of a single sideband voice signal?","answers":{"a":"A. 1 kHz","b":"B. 3 kHz","c":"C. 6 kHz","d":"D. 15 kHz"}},{"num":303,"sample":"T8A09","correct":"C","question":"What is the approximate bandwidth of a VHF repeater FM phone signal?","answers":{"a":"A. Less than 500 Hz","b":"B. About 150 kHz","c":"C. Between 5 and 15 kHz","d":"D. Between 50 and 125 kHz"}},{"num":304,"sample":"T8A10","correct":"B","question":"What is the typical bandwidth of analog fast-scan TV transmissions on the 70 cm band?","answers":{"a":"A. More than 10 MHz","b":"B. About 6 MHz","c":"C. About 3 MHz","d":"D. About 1 MHz"}},{"num":305,"sample":"T8A11","correct":"B","question":"What is the approximate maximum bandwidth required to transmit a CW signal?","answers":{"a":"A. 2.4 kHz","b":"B. 150 Hz","c":"C. 1000 Hz","d":"D. 15 kHz"}},{"num":306,"sample":"T8B01","correct":"D","question":"Who may be the control operator of a station communicating through an amateur satellite or space station?","answers":{"a":"A. Only an Amateur Extra Class operator","b":"B. A General Class licensee or higher licensee who has a satellite operator certification","c":"C. Only an Amateur Extra Class operator who is also an AMSAT member","d":"D. Any amateur whose license privileges allow them to transmit on the satellite uplink frequency"}},{"num":307,"sample":"T8B02","correct":"B","question":"[97.313(a)] How much transmitter power should be used on the uplink frequency of an amateur satellite or space station?","answers":{"a":"A. The maximum power of your transmitter","b":"B. The minimum amount of power needed to complete the contact","c":"C. No more than half the rating of your linear amplifier","d":"D. Never more than 1 watt"}},{"num":308,"sample":"T8B03","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following can be done using an amateur radio satellite?","answers":{"a":"A. Talk to amateur radio operators in other countries","b":"B. Get global positioning information","c":"C. Make telephone calls","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":309,"sample":"T8B04","correct":"B","question":"Which amateur stations may make contact with an amateur station on the International Space Station using 2 meter and 70 cm band amateur radio frequencies?","answers":{"a":"A. Only members of amateur radio clubs at NASA facilities","b":"B. Any amateur holding a Technician or higher class license","c":"C. Only the astronaut's family members who are hams","d":"D. You cannot talk to the ISS on amateur radio frequencies"}},{"num":310,"sample":"T8B05","correct":"D","question":"What is a satellite beacon?","answers":{"a":"A. The primary transmit antenna on the satellite","b":"B. An indicator light that that shows where to point your antenna","c":"C. A reflective surface on the satellite","d":"D. A transmission from a space station that contains information about a satellite"}},{"num":311,"sample":"T8B06","correct":"D","question":"What can be used to determine the time period during which an amateur satellite or space station can be accessed?","answers":{"a":"A. A GPS receiver","b":"B. A field strength meter","c":"C. A telescope","d":"D. A satellite tracking program"}},{"num":312,"sample":"T8B07","correct":"C","question":"With regard to satellite communications, what is Doppler shift?","answers":{"a":"A. A change in the satellite orbit","b":"B. A mode where the satellite receives signals on one band and transmits on another","c":"C. An observed change in signal frequency caused by relative motion between the satellite and the earth station","d":"D. A special digital communications mode for some satellites"}},{"num":313,"sample":"T8B08","correct":"B","question":"What is meant by the statement that a satellite is operating in \"mode U/V\"?","answers":{"a":"A. The satellite uplink is in the 15 meter band and the downlink is in the 10 meter band","b":"B. The satellite uplink is in the 70 cm band and the downlink is in the 2 meter band","c":"C. The satellite operates using ultraviolet frequencies","d":"D. The satellite frequencies are usually variable"}},{"num":314,"sample":"T8B09","correct":"B","question":"What causes \"spin fading\" when referring to satellite signals?","answers":{"a":"A. Circular polarized noise interference radiated from the sun","b":"B. Rotation of the satellite and its antennas","c":"C. Doppler shift of the received signal","d":"D. Interfering signals within the satellite uplink band"}},{"num":315,"sample":"T8B10","correct":"C","question":"What do the initials LEO tell you about an amateur satellite?","answers":{"a":"A. The satellite battery is in Low Energy Operation mode","b":"B. The satellite is performing a Lunar Ejection Orbit maneuver","c":"C. The satellite is in a Low Earth Orbit","d":"D. The satellite uses Light Emitting Optics"}},{"num":316,"sample":"T8B11","correct":"C","question":"What is a commonly used method of sending signals to and from a digital satellite?","answers":{"a":"A. USB AFSK","b":"B. PSK31","c":"C. FM Packet","d":"D. WSJT"}},{"num":317,"sample":"T8C01","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following methods is used to locate sources of noise interference or jamming?","answers":{"a":"A. Echolocation","b":"B. Doppler radar","c":"C. Radio direction finding","d":"D. Phase locking"}},{"num":318,"sample":"T8C02","correct":"B","question":"Which of these items would be useful for a hidden transmitter hunt?","answers":{"a":"A. Calibrated SWR meter","b":"B. A directional antenna","c":"C. A calibrated noise bridge","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":319,"sample":"T8C03","correct":"A","question":"What popular operating activity involves contacting as many stations as possible during a specified period of time?","answers":{"a":"A. Contesting","b":"B. Net operations","c":"C. Public service events","d":"D. Simulated emergency exercises"}},{"num":320,"sample":"T8C04","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following is good procedure when contacting another station in a radio contest?","answers":{"a":"A. Be sure to sign only the last two letters of your call if there is a pileup calling the station","b":"B. Work the station twice to be sure that you are in his log","c":"C. Send only the minimum information needed for proper identification and the contest exchange","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":321,"sample":"T8C05","correct":"A","question":"What is a grid locator?","answers":{"a":"A. A letter-number designator assigned to a geographic location","b":"B. A letter-number designator assigned to an azimuth and elevation","c":"C. An instrument for neutralizing a final amplifier","d":"D. An instrument for radio direction finding"}},{"num":322,"sample":"T8C06","correct":"C","question":"For what purpose is a temporary \"1 by 1\" format (letter-number-letter) call sign assigned?","answers":{"a":"A. To designate an experimental station","b":"B. To honor a deceased relative who was a radio amateur","c":"C. For operations in conjunction with an activity of special significance to the amateur community","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":323,"sample":"T8C07","correct":"B","question":"[97.215(c)] What is the maximum power allowed when transmitting telecommand signals to radio controlled models?","answers":{"a":"A. 500 milliwatts","b":"B. 1 watt","c":"C. 25 watts","d":"D. 1500 watts"}},{"num":324,"sample":"T8C08","correct":"C","question":"[97.215(a)] What is required in place of on-air station identification when sending signals to a radio control model using amateur frequencies?","answers":{"a":"A. Voice identification must be transmitted every 10 minutes","b":"B. Morse code ID must be sent once per hour","c":"C. A label indicating the licensee's name, call sign and address must be affixed to the transmitter","d":"D. A flag must be affixed to the transmitter antenna with the station call sign in 1 inch high letters or larger"}},{"num":325,"sample":"T8C09","correct":"C","question":"How might you obtain a list of active nodes that use VoIP?","answers":{"a":"A. From the FCC Rulebook","b":"B. From your local emergency coordinator","c":"C. From a repeater directory","d":"D. From the local repeater frequency coordinator"}},{"num":326,"sample":"T8C10","correct":"D","question":"How do you select a specific IRLP node when using a portable transceiver?","answers":{"a":"A. Choose a specific CTCSS tone","b":"B. Choose the correct DSC tone","c":"C. Access the repeater autopatch","d":"D. Use the keypad to transmit the IRLP node ID"}},{"num":327,"sample":"T8C11","correct":"A","question":"What name is given to an amateur radio station that is used to connect other amateur stations to the Internet?","answers":{"a":"A. A gateway","b":"B. A repeater","c":"C. A digipeater","d":"D. A beacon"}},{"num":328,"sample":"T8D01","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following is an example of a digital communications method?","answers":{"a":"A. Packet","b":"B. PSK31","c":"C. MFSK","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":329,"sample":"T8D02","correct":"A","question":"What does the term APRS mean?","answers":{"a":"A. Automatic Position Reporting System","b":"B. Associated Public Radio Station","c":"C. Auto Planning Radio Set-up","d":"D. Advanced Polar Radio System"}},{"num":330,"sample":"T8D03","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following is normally used when sending automatic location reports via amateur radio?","answers":{"a":"A. A connection to the vehicle speedometer","b":"B. A WWV receiver","c":"C. A connection to a broadcast FM sub-carrier receiver","d":"D. A Global Positioning System receiver"}},{"num":331,"sample":"T8D04","correct":"C","question":"What type of transmission is indicated by the term NTSC?","answers":{"a":"A. A Normal Transmission mode in Static Circuit","b":"B. A special mode for earth satellite uplink","c":"C. An analog fast scan color TV signal","d":"D. A frame compression scheme for TV signals"}},{"num":332,"sample":"T8D05","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following emission modes may be used by a Technician Class operator between 219 and 220 MHz?","answers":{"a":"A. Spread spectrum","b":"B. Data","c":"C. SSB voice","d":"D. Fast-scan television"}},{"num":333,"sample":"T8D06","correct":"B","question":"What does the abbreviation PSK mean?","answers":{"a":"A. Pulse Shift Keying","b":"B. Phase Shift Keying","c":"C. Packet Short Keying","d":"D. Phased Slide Keying"}},{"num":334,"sample":"T8D07","correct":"D","question":"What is PSK31?","answers":{"a":"A. A high-rate data transmission mode","b":"B. A method of reducing noise interference to FM signals","c":"C. A method of compressing digital television signal","d":"D. A low-rate data transmission mode"}},{"num":335,"sample":"T8D08","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following may be included in packet transmissions?","answers":{"a":"A. A check sum which permits error detection","b":"B. A header which contains the call sign of the station to which the information is being sent","c":"C. Automatic repeat request in case of error","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":336,"sample":"T8D09","correct":"C","question":"What code is used when sending CW in the amateur bands?","answers":{"a":"A. Baudot","b":"B. Hamming","c":"C. International Morse","d":"D. Gray"}},{"num":337,"sample":"T8D10","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following can be used to transmit CW in the amateur bands?","answers":{"a":"A. Straight Key","b":"B. Electronic Keyer","c":"C. Computer Keyboard","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":338,"sample":"T8D11","correct":"C","question":"What is a \"parity\" bit?","answers":{"a":"A. A control code required for automatic position reporting","b":"B. A timing bit used to ensure equal sharing of a frequency","c":"C. An extra code element used to detect errors in received data","d":"D. A \"triple width\" bit used to signal the end of a character"}},{"num":339,"sample":"T9A01","correct":"C","question":"What is a beam antenna?","answers":{"a":"A. An antenna built from aluminum I-beams","b":"B. An omnidirectional antenna invented by Clarence Beam","c":"C. An antenna that concentrates signals in one direction","d":"D. An antenna that reverses the phase of received signals"}},{"num":340,"sample":"T9A02","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following is true regarding vertical antennas?","answers":{"a":"A. The magnetic field is perpendicular to the Earth","b":"B. The electric field is perpendicular to the Earth","c":"C. The phase is inverted","d":"D. The phase is reversed"}},{"num":341,"sample":"T9A03","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following describes a simple dipole mounted so the conductor is parallel to the Earth's surface?","answers":{"a":"A. A ground wave antenna","b":"B. A horizontally polarized antenna","c":"C. A rhombic antenna","d":"D. A vertically polarized antenna"}},{"num":342,"sample":"T9A04","correct":"A","question":"What is a disadvantage of the \"rubber duck\" antenna supplied with most handheld radio transceivers?","answers":{"a":"A. It does not transmit or receive as effectively as a full-sized antenna","b":"B. It transmits a circularly polarized signal","c":"C. If the rubber end cap is lost it will unravel very quickly","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":343,"sample":"T9A05","correct":"C","question":"How would you change a dipole antenna to make it resonant on a higher frequency?","answers":{"a":"A. Lengthen it","b":"B. Insert coils in series with radiating wires","c":"C. Shorten it","d":"D. Add capacity hats to the ends of the radiating wires"}},{"num":344,"sample":"T9A06","correct":"C","question":"What type of antennas are the quad, Yagi, and dish?","answers":{"a":"A. Non-resonant antennas","b":"B. Loop antennas","c":"C. Directional antennas","d":"D. Isotropic antennas"}},{"num":345,"sample":"T9A07","correct":"A","question":"What is a good reason not to use a \"rubber duck\" antenna inside your car?","answers":{"a":"A. Signals can be significantly weaker than when it is outside of the vehicle","b":"B. It might cause your radio to overheat","c":"C. The SWR might decrease, decreasing the signal strength","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":346,"sample":"T9A08","correct":"C","question":"What is the approximate length, in inches, of a quarter-wavelength vertical antenna for 146 MHz?","answers":{"a":"A. 112","b":"B. 50","c":"C. 19","d":"D. 12"}},{"num":347,"sample":"T9A09","correct":"C","question":"What is the approximate length, in inches, of a 6 meter 1/2-wavelength wire dipole antenna?","answers":{"a":"A. 6","b":"B. 50","c":"C. 112","d":"D. 236"}},{"num":348,"sample":"T9A10","correct":"C","question":"In which direction is the radiation strongest from a half-wave dipole antenna in free space?","answers":{"a":"A. Equally in all directions","b":"B. Off the ends of the antenna","c":"C. Broadside to the antenna","d":"D. In the direction of the feedline"}},{"num":349,"sample":"T9A11","correct":"C","question":"What is meant by the gain of an antenna?","answers":{"a":"A. The additional power that is added to the transmitter power","b":"B. The additional power that is lost in the antenna when transmitting on a higher frequency","c":"C. The increase in signal strength in a specified direction when compared to a reference antenna","d":"D. The increase in impedance on receive or transmit compared to a reference antenna"}},{"num":350,"sample":"T9B01","correct":"B","question":"Why is it important to have a low SWR in an antenna system that uses coaxial cable feedline?","answers":{"a":"A. To reduce television interference","b":"B. To allow the efficient transfer of power and reduce losses","c":"C. To prolong antenna life","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":351,"sample":"T9B02","correct":"B","question":"What is the impedance of the most commonly used coaxial cable in typical amateur radio installations?","answers":{"a":"A. 8 ohms","b":"B. 50 ohms","c":"C. 600 ohms","d":"D. 12 ohms"}},{"num":352,"sample":"T9B03","correct":"A","question":"Why is coaxial cable used more often than any other feedline for amateur radio antenna systems?","answers":{"a":"A. It is easy to use and requires few special installation considerations","b":"B. It has less loss than any other type of feedline","c":"C. It can handle more power than any other type of feedline","d":"D. It is less expensive than any other types of feedline"}},{"num":353,"sample":"T9B04","correct":"A","question":"What does an antenna tuner do?","answers":{"a":"A. It matches the antenna system impedance to the transceiver's output impedance","b":"B. It helps a receiver automatically tune in weak stations","c":"C. It allows an antenna to be used on both transmit and receive","d":"D. It automatically selects the proper antenna for the frequency band being used"}},{"num":354,"sample":"T9B05","correct":"D","question":"What generally happens as the frequency of a signal passing through coaxial cable is increased?","answers":{"a":"A. The apparent SWR increases","b":"B. The reflected power increases","c":"C. The characteristic impedance increases","d":"D. The loss increases"}},{"num":355,"sample":"T9B06","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following connectors is most suitable for frequencies above 400 MHz?","answers":{"a":"A. A UHF (PL-259/SO-239) connector","b":"B. A Type N connector","c":"C. An RS-213 connector","d":"D. A DB-23 connector"}},{"num":356,"sample":"T9B07","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following is true of PL-259 type coax connectors?","answers":{"a":"A. They are good for UHF frequencies","b":"B. They are water tight","c":"C. The are commonly used at HF frequencies","d":"D. They are a bayonet type connector"}},{"num":357,"sample":"T9B08","correct":"A","question":"Why should coax connectors exposed to the weather be sealed against water intrusion?","answers":{"a":"A. To prevent an increase in feedline loss","b":"B. To prevent interference to telephones","c":"C. To keep the jacket from becoming loose","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":358,"sample":"T9B09","correct":"B","question":"What might cause erratic changes in SWR readings?","answers":{"a":"A. The transmitter is being modulated","b":"B. A loose connection in an antenna or a feedline","c":"C. The transmitter is being over-modulated","d":"D. Interference from other stations is distorting your signal"}},{"num":359,"sample":"T9B10","correct":"C","question":"What electrical difference exists between the smaller RG-58 and larger RG-8 coaxial cables?","answers":{"a":"A. There is no significant difference between the two types","b":"B. RG-58 cable has less loss at a given frequency","c":"C. RG-8 cable has less loss at a given frequency","d":"D. RG-58 cable can handle higher power levels"}},{"num":360,"sample":"T9B11","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following types of feedline has the lowest loss at VHF and UHF?","answers":{"a":"A. 50-ohm flexible coax","b":"B. Multi-conductor unbalanced cable","c":"C. Air-insulated hard line","d":"D. 75-ohm flexible coax"}},{"num":361,"sample":"T0A01","correct":"B","question":"Which is a commonly accepted value for the lowest voltage that can cause a dangerous electric shock?","answers":{"a":"A. 12 volts","b":"B. 30 volts","c":"C. 120 volts","d":"D. 300 volts"}},{"num":362,"sample":"T0A02","correct":"D","question":"How does current flowing through the body cause a health hazard?","answers":{"a":"A. By heating tissue","b":"B. It disrupts the electrical functions of cells","c":"C. It causes involuntary muscle contractions","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":363,"sample":"T0A03","correct":"C","question":"What is connected to the green wire in a three-wire electrical AC plug?","answers":{"a":"A. Neutral","b":"B. Hot","c":"C. Safety ground","d":"D. The white wire"}},{"num":364,"sample":"T0A04","correct":"B","question":"What is the purpose of a fuse in an electrical circuit?","answers":{"a":"A. To prevent power supply ripple from damaging a circuit","b":"B. To interrupt power in case of overload","c":"C. To limit current to prevent shocks","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":365,"sample":"T0A05","correct":"C","question":"Why is it unwise to install a 20-ampere fuse in the place of a 5-ampere fuse?","answers":{"a":"A. The larger fuse would be likely to blow because it is rated for higher current","b":"B. The power supply ripple would greatly increase","c":"C. Excessive current could cause a fire","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":366,"sample":"T0A06","correct":"D","question":"What is a good way to guard against electrical shock at your station?","answers":{"a":"A. Use three-wire cords and plugs for all AC powered equipment","b":"B. Connect all AC powered station equipment to a common safety ground","c":"C. Use a circuit protected by a ground-fault interrupter","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":367,"sample":"T0A07","correct":"D","question":"Which of these precautions should be taken when installing devices for lightning protection in a coaxial cable feedline?","answers":{"a":"A. Include a parallel bypass switch for each protector so that it can be switched out of the circuit when running high power","b":"B. Include a series switch in the ground line of each protector to prevent RF overload from inadvertently damaging the protector","c":"C. Keep the ground wires from each protector separate and connected to station ground","d":"D. Ground all of the protectors to a common plate which is in turn connected to an external ground"}},{"num":368,"sample":"T0A08","correct":"C","question":"What is one way to recharge a 12-volt lead-acid station battery if the commercial power is out?","answers":{"a":"A. Cool the battery in ice for several hours","b":"B. Add acid to the battery","c":"C. Connect the battery to a car's battery and run the engine","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":369,"sample":"T0A09","correct":"C","question":"What kind of hazard is presented by a conventional 12-volt storage battery?","answers":{"a":"A. It emits ozone which can be harmful to the atmosphere","b":"B. Shock hazard due to high voltage","c":"C. Explosive gas can collect if not properly vented","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":370,"sample":"T0A10","correct":"A","question":"What can happen if a lead-acid storage battery is charged or discharged too quickly?","answers":{"a":"A. The battery could overheat and give off flammable gas or explode","b":"B. The voltage can become reversed","c":"C. The \"memory effect\" will reduce the capacity of the battery","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":371,"sample":"T0A11","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following is good practice when installing ground wires on a tower for lightning protection?","answers":{"a":"A. Put a loop in the ground connection to prevent water damage to the ground system","b":"B. Make sure that all bends in the ground wires are clean, right angle bends","c":"C. Ensure that connections are short and direct","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":372,"sample":"T0A12","correct":"D","question":"What kind of hazard might exist in a power supply when it is turned off and disconnected?","answers":{"a":"A. Static electricity could damage the grounding system","b":"B. Circulating currents inside the transformer might cause damage","c":"C. The fuse might blow if you remove the cover","d":"D. You might receive an electric shock from stored charge in large capacitors"}},{"num":373,"sample":"T0A13","correct":"A","question":"What safety equipment should always be included in home-built equipment that is powered from 120V AC power circuits?","answers":{"a":"A. A fuse or circuit breaker in series with the AC \"hot\" conductor","b":"B. An AC voltmeter across the incoming power source","c":"C. An inductor in series with the AC power source","d":"D. A capacitor across the AC power source"}},{"num":374,"sample":"T0B01","correct":"C","question":"When should members of a tower work team wear a hard hat and safety glasses?","answers":{"a":"A. At all times except when climbing the tower","b":"B. At all times except when belted firmly to the tower","c":"C. At all times when any work is being done on the tower","d":"D. Only when the tower exceeds 30 feet in height"}},{"num":375,"sample":"T0B02","correct":"C","question":"What is a good precaution to observe before climbing an antenna tower?","answers":{"a":"A. Make sure that you wear a grounded wrist strap","b":"B. Remove all tower grounding connections","c":"C. Put on a climbing harness and safety glasses","d":"D. All of the these choices are correct"}},{"num":376,"sample":"T0B03","correct":"D","question":"Under what circumstances is it safe to climb a tower without a helper or observer?","answers":{"a":"A. When no electrical work is being performed","b":"B. When no mechanical work is being performed","c":"C. When the work being done is not more than 20 feet above the ground","d":"D. Never"}},{"num":377,"sample":"T0B04","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following is an important safety precaution to observe when putting up an antenna tower?","answers":{"a":"A. Wear a ground strap connected to your wrist at all times","b":"B. Insulate the base of the tower to avoid lightning strikes","c":"C. Look for and stay clear of any overhead electrical wires","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":378,"sample":"T0B05","correct":"C","question":"What is the purpose of a gin pole?","answers":{"a":"A. To temporarily replace guy wires","b":"B. To be used in place of a safety harness","c":"C. To lift tower sections or antennas","d":"D. To provide a temporary ground"}},{"num":379,"sample":"T0B06","correct":"D","question":"What is the minimum safe distance from a power line to allow when installing an antenna?","answers":{"a":"A. Half the width of your property","b":"B. The height of the power line above ground","c":"C. 1/2 wavelength at the operating frequency","d":"D. So that if the antenna falls unexpectedly, no part of it can come closer than 10 feet to the power wires"}},{"num":380,"sample":"T0B07","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following is an important safety rule to remember when using a crank-up tower?","answers":{"a":"A. This type of tower must never be painted","b":"B. This type of tower must never be grounded","c":"C. This type of tower must never be climbed unless it is in the fully retracted position","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":381,"sample":"T0B08","correct":"C","question":"What is considered to be a proper grounding method for a tower?","answers":{"a":"A. A single four-foot ground rod, driven into the ground no more than 12 inches from the base","b":"B. A ferrite-core RF choke connected between the tower and ground","c":"C. Separate eight-foot long ground rods for each tower leg, bonded to the tower and each other","d":"D. A connection between the tower base and a cold water pipe"}},{"num":382,"sample":"T0B09","correct":"C","question":"Why should you avoid attaching an antenna to a utility pole?","answers":{"a":"A. The antenna will not work properly because of induced voltages","b":"B. The utility company will charge you an extra monthly fee","c":"C. The antenna could contact high-voltage power wires","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":383,"sample":"T0B10","correct":"C","question":"Which of the following is true concerning grounding conductors used for lightning protection?","answers":{"a":"A. Only non-insulated wire must be used","b":"B. Wires must be carefully routed with precise right-angle bends","c":"C. Sharp bends must be avoided","d":"D. Common grounds must be avoided"}},{"num":384,"sample":"T0B11","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following establishes grounding requirements for an amateur radio tower or antenna?","answers":{"a":"A. FCC Part 97 Rules","b":"B. Local electrical codes","c":"C. FAA tower lighting regulations","d":"D. Underwriters Laboratories' recommended practices"}},{"num":385,"sample":"T0C01","correct":"D","question":"What type of radiation are VHF and UHF radio signals?","answers":{"a":"A. Gamma radiation","b":"B. Ionizing radiation","c":"C. Alpha radiation","d":"D. Non-ionizing radiation"}},{"num":386,"sample":"T0C02","correct":"B","question":"Which of the following frequencies has the lowest Maximum Permissible Exposure limit?","answers":{"a":"A. 3.5 MHz","b":"B. 50 MHz","c":"C. 440 MHz","d":"D. 1296 MHz"}},{"num":387,"sample":"T0C03","correct":"C","question":"What is the maximum power level that an amateur radio station may use at VHF frequencies before an RF exposure evaluation is required?","answers":{"a":"A. 1500 watts PEP transmitter output","b":"B. 1 watt forward power","c":"C. 50 watts PEP at the antenna","d":"D. 50 watts PEP reflected power"}},{"num":388,"sample":"T0C04","correct":"D","question":"What factors affect the RF exposure of people near an amateur station antenna?","answers":{"a":"A. Frequency and power level of the RF field","b":"B. Distance from the antenna to a person","c":"C. Radiation pattern of the antenna","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":389,"sample":"T0C05","correct":"D","question":"Why do exposure limits vary with frequency?","answers":{"a":"A. Lower frequency RF fields have more energy than higher frequency fields","b":"B. Lower frequency RF fields do not penetrate the human body","c":"C. Higher frequency RF fields are transient in nature","d":"D. The human body absorbs more RF energy at some frequencies than at others"}},{"num":390,"sample":"T0C06","correct":"D","question":"Which of the following is an acceptable method to determine that your station complies with FCC RF exposure regulations?","answers":{"a":"A. By calculation based on FCC OET Bulletin 65","b":"B. By calculation based on computer modeling","c":"C. By measurement of field strength using calibrated equipment","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":391,"sample":"T0C07","correct":"B","question":"What could happen if a person accidentally touched your antenna while you were transmitting?","answers":{"a":"A. Touching the antenna could cause television interference","b":"B. They might receive a painful RF burn","c":"C. They might develop radiation poisoning","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":392,"sample":"T0C08","correct":"A","question":"Which of the following actions might amateur operators take to prevent exposure to RF radiation in excess of FCC-supplied limits?","answers":{"a":"A. Relocate antennas","b":"B. Relocate the transmitter","c":"C. Increase the duty cycle","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":393,"sample":"T0C09","correct":"B","question":"How can you make sure your station stays in compliance with RF safety regulations?","answers":{"a":"A. By informing the FCC of any changes made in your station","b":"B. By re-evaluating the station whenever an item of equipment is changed","c":"C. By making sure your antennas have low SWR","d":"D. All of these choices are correct"}},{"num":394,"sample":"T0C10","correct":"A","question":"Why is duty cycle one of the factors used to determine safe RF radiation exposure levels?","answers":{"a":"A. It affects the average exposure of people to radiation","b":"B. It affects the peak exposure of people to radiation","c":"C. It takes into account the antenna feedline loss","d":"D. It takes into account the thermal effects of the final amplifier"}},{"num":395,"sample":"T0C11","correct":"C","question":"What is meant by \"duty cycle\" when referring to RF exposure?","answers":{"a":"A. The difference between lowest usable output and maximum rated output power of a transmitter","b":"B. The difference between PEP and average power of an SSB signal","c":"C. The ratio of on-air time to total operating time of a transmitted signal","d":"D. The amount of time the operator spends transmitting"}}]);
